<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The gospel minister's maintenance vindicated Wherein, a regular ministry in the churches, is first asserted, and the objections against a Gospel maintenance for ministers, answered. Also, the dignity, necessity, difficulty, use and excellency of the ministry of Christ is opened. Likewise, the nature and vveghtiness of that sacred vvork and office clearly evinc'd. Recommended to the baptized congregations, by several elders in and about the City of London.</title>
            <author>Knollys, Hanserd, 1599?-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 150 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 75 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47561</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing K711A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R213604</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99825941</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99825941</idno>
            <idno type="VID">30333</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47561)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 30333)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1796:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The gospel minister's maintenance vindicated Wherein, a regular ministry in the churches, is first asserted, and the objections against a Gospel maintenance for ministers, answered. Also, the dignity, necessity, difficulty, use and excellency of the ministry of Christ is opened. Likewise, the nature and vveghtiness of that sacred vvork and office clearly evinc'd. Recommended to the baptized congregations, by several elders in and about the City of London.</title>
                  <author>Knollys, Hanserd, 1599?-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12], 132 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed, and are to be sold by John Harris at the Harrow, in the Poultrey,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Preface signed: Hanserd Knollys [and ten others].</note>
                  <note>Running title reads: The Gospel ministers maintenance vindicated.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Clergy --  Legal status, laws, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:1"/>
            <p>THE Goſpel Miniſter's <hi>
                  <hi rend="blackletterType">Maintenance</hi> VINDICATED.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>WHEREIN, A Regular Miniſtry in the Churches, is firſt
Aſſerted, and the Objections againſt a Goſpel Maintenance for
Miniſters, Anſwered.</p>
            <p>ALSO, The Dignity, Neceſſity, Difficulty, Uſe and Excellency
of the Miniſtry of Chriſt is opened.</p>
            <p>LIKEWISE, The Nature and VVeightineſs of that Sacred VVork and
Office clearly evinc'd.</p>
            <p>Recommended to the Baptized Congregations, by ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Elders in
and about the City of <hi>London.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <bibl>2 Cor 9.14.</bibl> 
               <p>Even ſo hath the Lord Ordained, That they who Preach the
Goſpel ſhall live of the Goſp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>2 Cor. 2.16.</bibl> 
               <p>And who is ſufficient for
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> things.</p>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London</hi> Printed, and are to be ſold by <hi>Jo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> at the <hi>Harrow,</hi> in
the <hi>Poul<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="errata">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>ERRATA.</head>
            <p>PAge 2. Line 12. and 15. for <hi>Church,</hi> Read
<hi>Churches.</hi> p. 3. l. 9. f. <hi>Church</hi> r. <hi>Churches.</hi> p. 5.
l. 22. r. <hi>the.</hi> p. 7. l. 11. and 14. f. <hi>the Churches Duty,
ſhe;</hi> r. <hi>the Duty of the Churches, they.</hi> p. 8. l. 7. r.
<hi>Churches,</hi> and l. 9. f. <hi>her.</hi> r. <hi>their.</hi> p. 14. l. 2.
r. <hi>Churches.</hi> p. 20. l. 1. <hi>h. is wanting.</hi> p. 20. l. 21. <hi>s.
is wanting.</hi> p. 25. <hi>f. contangle</hi> r. <hi>intangle.</hi> p. 32. l.
18. f. <hi>their</hi> r. <hi>her.</hi> p. 41. l. 22. f. <hi>are</hi> r.
<hi>do.</hi> p. 47. l. 21. f. <hi>let.</hi> r. <hi>ſet.</hi> p. 70. l. 26. f.
<hi>and</hi> r. <hi>or.</hi> p. 101. l. 10. r. <hi>Family.</hi> p. 105. l. 14.
leave out <hi>ſay they.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:2"/>
            <head>To the Congregations of Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tized Believers in <hi>England</hi>
and <hi>Wales,</hi> Grace, Mercy and Peace be multiplied through the ſaving
Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Beloved Brethren,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>WE have <hi>read</hi> and <hi>con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered</hi> of <hi>this
enſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Treatiſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and do
conclude in may be of great profit to the Churches of Jeſus Chriſt; we
fearing ſome <hi>Congregations</hi> have
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>uly <hi>weighed</hi> and
<hi>conſidered,</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>r
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>diſpenſible Duty to the
Miniſtry; in reſpect of providing ſuch a <hi>Maintenance,</hi> for
thoſe who Labour amongſt them, and are
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> them in the Lord, as they ought
to do,<pb facs="tcp:30333:3"/>by which means (it may he feared that) many of them may be
hindred or obſtruct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in attending on their Work, in ſerving of Chriſt
and his People, as the Nature of their <hi>ſacred Imployment</hi> and
<hi>Office</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires, and the <hi>preſent Day eſpecially calls
for,</hi> and as <hi>the Lord himſelf hath alſo Ordained:</hi> Therefore,
our earneſt Deſires are, that our Brethren, both <hi>Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters</hi> and
<hi>Members,</hi> would he pleaſed to get this little Book, and both Read and
w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ll Weigh, what is ſaid therein,
without Preju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dice, <hi>both</hi> in Reſpect of a <hi>Regular
Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtry,</hi> the <hi>Miniſters Maintenance,</hi> and the <hi>Greatneſs
and Difficulty</hi> of <hi>their Work;</hi> and now, that it may be bleſſed
by JEHOVAH, to the Great and Good Ends it is deſigned, is, and ſhall be,
the Hearty Prayers of us, your Brethren, in the Faith and Fellowſhip of the
Goſpel of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed> 
                  <list>
                     <item>Hanſerd Knollys,</item>
                     <item>William Kiffin,</item>
                     <item>William Collins,</item>
                     <item>John Harris,</item>
                     <item>George Barret,</item>
                     <item>Richard Adams,</item>
                     <item>Benjamin Keach,</item>
                     <item>Iſaac Lamb,</item>
                     <item>Edward Man,</item>
                     <item>Leonard Harriſon,</item>
                     <item>Hercules Collins,</item>
                  </list>
               </signed> 
               <dateline>London,<date>July, 30.
1681.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:3"/>
            <head>The Contents of the chief Things in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſted on in the
enſuing Treatiſe.</head>
            <list>
               <item>A Regular Miniſtry Aſſerted. <hi>Pag. 1</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Chriſt himſelf in his own Perſon<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> firſt
ſettled the Miniſtry in a moſt ſolemn manner. <hi>3</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Power left to particular Congregations to chooſe their own
Miniſters. <hi>6</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Churches ought to take care that they chooſe Men to Office,
that are competently qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lified, according to <hi>1 Tim. 3.1,2,3.</hi> And
<hi>Tit. 1.6.9: 7 8</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Churches after Election and Tryal of their Miniſters ought
ſolemnly to ordain them by Prayer and Impoſition of Hands. <hi>8
9</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Churches undue Proceedings in the choice of Elders,
diſhonourable; and an hinderance to the Goſpel. <hi>10 11</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Every Congregation that neglects their Duty in providing a
fit Maintenance for their Paſtors, if able, is diſhonourable, and a
ſcandal to Religion. <hi>13</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:30333:4"/>Miniſters Maintenance Aſſerted ſtrange
that any ſhould doubt of it, <hi>13 14</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Scriptures urged, to prove 'tis an indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpenſable
Duty, to provide a comfortable Livelyhood for Faithful Miniſters. <hi>15
16</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>13 Arguments to prove this Duty.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>1.</hi> Chriſt would not have his Diſciples, when he
firſt ſent them out, waſte their own Subſtance, whilſt imployed in
his Work. <hi>17 18</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>2.</hi> God has poſitively ordained, or appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted his
Miniſters a comfortable Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance under the Goſpel. <hi>19
20</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Miniſters Maintenance not now by Tithes, as it was under
the Law. <hi>20 21</hi>
               </item>
               <item>No denying or avoiding the Duty of Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters Maintenance.
<hi>22 23</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>3.</hi> Miniſters commanded to attend wholly upon their
Work. <hi>25</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Nothing but real Neceſſity, will admit him to diſpence
with the contrary, all his time little enough. <hi>26</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Paſtors muſt viſit their Members, go from Houſe to
Houſe. <hi>27</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>4.</hi> Miniſters that follow Trades, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
ex<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>poſes them to Reproach, therefore if poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible to be avoided. <hi>30
31</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:30333:4"/>
                  <hi>5.</hi> Miniſters Maintenance, proved by
the Law and Light of Nature, as well as by the poſitive Law of Chriſt.
<hi>32 33</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Obj.</hi> Some Miniſters do not need it.
<hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered. 40</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>6</hi> Miniſters not unable to follow Trades, ſome
could do it, and provide for them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and get Eſtates as well as
others; therefore ought not to ſuffer for taking that ſacred work upon
them. <hi>43</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Miniſters are as much bound to provide for their Families
as other Men. <hi>43 44</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>7</hi> Shewing what great Proviſion God made for his
Miniſters under the Law, proving the Equitableneſs of the ſame Law
remains ſtill. <hi>45 46</hi>
               </item>
               <item>As great Reaſon for the People to provide for their
Miniſters under the Goſpel; nay, greater in ſome Reſpects, than for
them under the Law <hi>47</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>8.</hi> Elders or Paſtors muſt be given to
Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpitality; therefore, if Churches are able, and they poor, they ought to
put them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a capacity to ſhine in that Virtue. <hi>47 48</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>9.</hi> This duty urged from the Honoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleneſs of it,
it frees Members from the ſenſure of Coveteouſneſs; one part<pb facs="tcp:30333:5"/>of that double Honour due to Elders that Labour in the Word, proved to
be Maintenance. <hi>50 51 52</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>10.</hi> Argued for, from the ſaid Effects and
Inconveniences that attends the neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect of it. <hi>52 53 54</hi>
               </item>
               <item>It lays a Diſcouragement in the way of good Men, to give
themſelves to Study and Dedicate themſelves to take part in the Miniſtry.
<hi>54 55</hi>
               </item>
               <item>It expoſes Miniſters to neglect their Work, when they are
neglected, nay, to leave it, and be blameleſs. <hi>56 57</hi>
               </item>
               <item>This neglect hinders Miniſters in their Stu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, they having
not time, and ſo Preach no better, its neceſſary for Miniſters to have
ſtore of Uſeful Books, and Time alſo. <hi>58 59</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>11.</hi> Neglect to Miniſters, and the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern of
God's Houſe, is a robbing of God, and may bring a blaſt upon Men's
E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates. <hi>62 63 64 65 66</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>12.</hi> A ſhame to God's People, to ſuffer the
Heathens and Papiſts to do more to up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold Idolatry, than they do to uphold
the true Worſhip of the Living God. <hi>71 72</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>13.</hi> Miniſters will be left wholly without 
<pb facs="tcp:30333:5"/>excuſe, if they do not faithfully fulfil their Miniſtry, when
the Congregations ſufficiently provide for them, <hi>74 75</hi>
               </item>
               <item>One Miniſter took off of Worldly Buſineſs, may do more
in promulgating the Goſpel, than ſeveral others who are not. <hi>76
77</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Motives to preſs this Duty.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Motive 1.</hi> Miniſters repreſent Chriſt, what
done to them is done to him. <hi>77 78</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Motive 2.</hi> Miniſters being intruſted with our
Souls, we ought to take care they want nothing that is neceſſary for their
Bodies. <hi>78 79</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Motive 3.</hi> Miniſters being expoſed to ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny
Temptations and Diſcouragements, a great Motive why, not to be left to
ſerve in wants and neceſſities. <hi>80 81</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Motive 4.</hi> Miniſters may forbear work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing if they
will, provided the Church can provide for them, and they faithfully diſcharge
their Duty. <hi>81 82</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Queſt.</hi> May a Paſtor make Terms with a Church
about his Maintenance, before he take the charge of them? <hi>Anſwered.
82</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Queſt.</hi> What ſhall that Church do that is not
able to provide for her Paſtor? <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered. 83 84 85</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:30333:6"/>
                  <hi>Queſt.</hi> Have not you diſclaimed
againſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſuch who Preach for
Hire? A Three<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fold <hi>Anſwer</hi> given. <hi>87 8<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Obj.</hi> Is there any Reaſon that Rich Men th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> are Paſtors ſhould have an Allowance<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  <hi>Anſwered. 89 9<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Obj.</hi> Our Church is ſmall, our Paſtor can<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>not
take up all his Time in Spiritual Ser<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vice. <hi>Anſwered. 92 9<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Reaſon why ſome Churches are ſmall<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> may be,
becauſe Miniſters are no mor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
Labourous in Preaching the Goſpel up an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> down in the adjacent places where the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Live, which ſome can't do becauſe n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> in capacity. The preſent Liberty to
b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Improved. Idle and ſlothful
Miniſter not to be maintained. <hi>93 94 95 96</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Two Reaſons of ſome Paſtors Remiſneſs i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Preaching, or Labouring no more. <hi>97
98</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Miniſters may Work with their Hands, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ought ſo to do when it will tend to
th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> furtherance of the Goſpel.
<hi>10<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>A great Harveſt now, and good Weather<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> therefore,
Miniſters ought to Labou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> hard.
<hi>101 10<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>Freely you have received, freely give. <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſwered. 103
10<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <pb facs="tcp:30333:6"/>Miniſters not to Preach for Hire, <hi>i.
e.</hi> to propound that as their end. <hi>186</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Congregations ought to give the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters their
Portion, with Reſpect and Honour. <hi>108</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Miniſters Work now as great and weighty as thoſe was
under the Law, like Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity of their Work, 'tis as Honourable, neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect
as dangerous as then: People now as great Benefit by the Miniſtry, or more;
from hence, the ſame Reaſon for their Maintenance as under the Law.
<hi>111</hi>
               </item>
               <item>May he that Exerciſes his Gift but now and then, expect an
Allowance from the Church. <hi>Anſwered. 112</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Weightineſs of the Miniſters Work opened. <hi>113
114</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Their Work is Honourable, they are in a high Sphere,
intruſted with the higheſt concerns in the World. <hi>114</hi>
               </item>
               <item>They Workers with Chriſt. <hi>115</hi>
               </item>
               <item>May be in danger of loſing the Souls of Men. <hi>117
118</hi>
               </item>
               <item>They muſt have a Regulur Call. <hi>120</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Miniſters intruſted with the Charge of the Church.
<hi>122</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>eir Work
difficult in <hi>5</hi> Reſpects. <hi>127,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>28, 129.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
         <div type="notice">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:7"/>
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>READER,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>WHereas, in the 38th. <hi>Article of Religio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> (called, <hi>The Thirty Nine Articles</hi> of
th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Church of <hi>England;</hi>)
'tis ſaid, <hi>The Riches an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
Goods of Chriſtians are not common, as touching th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Right, Title, and Poſſeſſion of the ſame, as
certa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Anabaptiſts <hi>do
falſly boaſt.</hi> We look upon o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſelves concerned to declare, (that if there we<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> in the Laſt Age, in
<hi>Germany,</hi> or elſewhere, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> People bearing that Name, who Aſſerted any ſuc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> thing;) we know none called
<hi>Anabaptiſts</hi> in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>land,</hi> nor any where elſe, who hold
that abſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> or rotten Principle;
but do <hi>teſtifie</hi> our <hi>diſlike</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>abhorrence of it,</hi> and verily believe, as 'tis
in<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mated in the ſaid
<hi>Article, That the Goods, Riche<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
and Poſſeſſions of all Chriſtians, as touching t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ght and
title of the ſame are their own,</hi> as t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Scripture
witneſſes, <hi>Acts</hi> 5.4. Yet notwit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtanding we alſo believe and teach, that <hi>ev<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> man ought of ſuch things as he
poſſeſſeth liberal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> to give
Alms to the poor according to his Abili<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> as is alſo there aſſerted. Having this opport<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nity, we thought it not amiſs to
publiſh this clear our ſelves and our Brethren, from t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſcandal, which poſſibly ſome may caſt upon
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſince theſe Articles (by
reaſon of a late Act <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this
preſent <hi>Parliament</hi>) are more genera<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>own and examined by
many People.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:7"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="section">
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:8"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:30333:8"/>
            <head>A Regular Miniſtry in the Church Aſſerted.</head>
            <p>GOD in his Infinite Goodneſs having by his preſent
Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dences, not only given us re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ite from our former Sufferings, but
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>e truſt begun that great and
glorious <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ork of the Churches
Deliverance <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> long the hope and
expectation of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> that truly love
and fear the Lord; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>e cannot but
look upon our Selves <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ncerned to
endeavour to make a due <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>provement
of that Mercy and Good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ſs that
is attending us herein; and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ing
into conſideration the Condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n
of the Church of Jeſus Chriſt, we
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>not but be concerned with, and 
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:30333:9"/>afflicted for the late and preſent wants She lies under in
reſpect to the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, God having of late Years re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved ſo many able
and pious Men, and ſeems to be near the removing many more by. Age and Bodily
Infir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mities. This with other things put us upon the Conſideration how much
the Honour of Chriſt, the reputation of his Glorious Goſpel in the World;
as likewiſe, the Good and Well-being of the Church depends upon a regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar
and orderly Miniſtry, and the Continuation thereof: And for the Church to be
under a ſupine neglect herein is very ſad.</p>
            <p>Firſt, <hi>Either in not endeavouring af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and calling forth
ſuch a regular and ſtated Miniſtry, according to Goſpel Inſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tution
at all; or,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Secondly, <hi>to be ſo weak and inadverte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> as to call forth ſuch as are not ſo duly
fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhed and qualified for it; or,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Thirdly, <hi>Suffering ſuch as are call'<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> forth to this great Work under compete<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Abilities, to lye under
unſupportable Bur<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>thens, <pb n="3" facs="tcp:30333:9"/>muſt needs be greatly blameable
before our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, the great Biſhop and Shepherd of our Souls,
as well as highly negligent of their own Edification and Well-being.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. To proceed, it cannot be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nied but Chriſt hath, and
ought to have, a ſtated and regular Miniſtry in his Church, according to
his own Inſtitution: Who himſelf, when he entred upon his Miniſtry, here
on Earth, did call forth Apoſtles and Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples to bear that part of the
Work with him, which he called them to, and fitted
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hem for: See <hi>Mark,</hi> 3.13.
to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>. <hi>Chriſt went up into
a Mountain, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>d called to him whom
he would, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>hey came to him, and
he ordained Twelve <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>at they
ſhould be with Him, and that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e
might ſend them forth to Preach; to
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hom He gave the Name of
Apoſtles.</hi> Mat. 10.2. Luke 6.13. Which he did
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ith great Solemnity and Invocation
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Father (for <hi>he
continued all <pb n="4" facs="tcp:30333:10"/>Night in Prayer to God) and when it was Day he
choſe the Twelve, and Named them Apoſtles.</hi> After which he ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
other Seventy, <hi>and ſent them forth by Two; and Two, before His Face, to
every City and Place,</hi> &amp;c. which were la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourers with Him in the
Harveſt, V. 2. And He commanded them to give themſelves up to the Work he
had cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led them to, and not take Care what they ſhould Eat or Drink, <hi>For
the La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourer</hi> (ſaith he) <hi>is worthy of his Hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Ver. to 14. Here our Lord Jeſus Chriſt
Himſelf did Inſtitute and Lay the Foundation of the Goſpel Miniſtry in
His own Authority; and accordingly takes care for the continuance of it af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
His Death and Reſurrection, and actual Inveſtiture in our Nature of a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Power in Heaven and Earth, <hi>Mat<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> 28.18.19.20. <hi>And Jeſus came
an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſpake unto them, ſaying, All
Power <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> given unto me in Heaven
and in Earth<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Go ye therefore Teach all Nations,</hi> &amp;<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>And lo I am with you always, even
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the End of the World.</hi>
Amen. Alſo after <pb n="5" facs="tcp:30333:10"/>His Bleſſed and Glorious Aſcention,
and <hi>Sitting on the Throne of the Majeſty in the Heavens.</hi> Heb. 8.<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>. <hi>Angels, and Authorities, and
Powers being made ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject unto him.</hi> 1 Pet. 3. &amp; 22. Did by His
Apoſtles give Commandment and Direction for the continuance hereof to the end
of the World, and his Second <hi>Coming without Sin unto Salvation.</hi> Heb.
9.28. As <hi>Acts</hi> 14.21,22,23. After they had by their Miniſtry been
bleſt with the Converſion of many Souls, they took care to direct them into
the Duty of Church Communion; and by their Suffrages, <hi>Ordained them Elders
in every Church.</hi> So the Apoſtle gives this as the Reaſon, Why he
<hi>left</hi> Titus <hi>in</hi> Creete; (he not having opportunity after
Prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching the Goſpel to them) to put things into due Order. <hi>Tit.</hi>
1.5. <hi>That he ſhould ſet in Order the things that were wanting</hi> (or
left undone by the Apoſtle) <hi>and Or
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e Elders in every City:</hi> that
is Church in euery City, as before, <hi>Acts</hi> 14. who are called
<hi>Elders, Biſhops, or Paſtors,</hi> and<pb n="6" facs="tcp:30333:11"/>
               <hi>Teachers;</hi> Names ſignificative of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Authority, Office and Work.</p>
            <p n="2">2. Chriſt being now in Heaven and an extraordinary Call
being ceaſed the Scriptures being a perfect and ſtanding Rule to the Church
through all Ages, he has committed this Care to her ſelf, according to the
Power given to Her, who is <hi>the Pillar and Ground of Truth,</hi> to provide
Miniſters for her own Edification, in Obedience to his Commands and Rules
given in his word, as he ſhall ſee good to Bleſs her with Spiritual Gifts
and Abilities, in order to the fitting them for this Work; the Father alſo
has Covenanted to give his Spirit in the Gifts and Graces of it, and promiſed
that the Words <hi>he has put into Chriſts Mouth, and the ſpirit that is
upon him, ſhall never depart from him, nor his ſeeds ſeed, for ever:</hi>
Likewiſe has accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Circumſtances of time the Church hath been
under, bleſt her, as with his Grace ſo with all needful Spiritual Gifts.
<hi>Eph.</hi> 4.7.11. <hi>For the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fecting the ſaints for the Work of the
Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry,<pb n="7" facs="tcp:30333:11"/>for the Edifying the Body of Chriſt.</hi> So
that whilſt there is a Church Milli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tant, Saints on this ſide Perfection,
any of the Members of Chriſt Myſtical Body on Earth, thoſe Spiritual
Gifts needfull to their preſent State, ſhall be given, and be amongſt
them, for the Support of the great Ordinance of the Miniſtry, and for the
good of the Church.</p>
            <p n="3">3. And as its the Churches Duty to Seek theſe Spiritual
Abilities, and improve them when they are given to theſe great and Holy Ends;
ſo ſhe muſt walk regularly herein, in obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence to the Rules given by
Chriſt in this Caſe; who hath laid down the qualifications both Negative
and Poſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive, of all ſuch as ought to be called to this great work and
Truſt of Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtring by Office, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 3.1. to 9. <hi>Tit.</hi>
1.6.9. we have no warrant to put any into the Miniſtry otherwiſe, ſave
ſuch as are here diſcribed, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petently fitted for it. For as it was a
ſin of Old in the Church to put any into<pb n="8" facs="tcp:30333:12"/>the Miniſtry,
but thoſe whom God appointed by the Rules given to them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſo it can be
no leſs Evil for the Church now, to call any forth into Office, but ſuch
who are qualified as God's Word directs; and now, as Chriſt hath made this
grant of Power to the Church of chooſing her own Officers for her
Edifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation; ſo he hath left Rules for her, who, and how to choſe, as we
ſaid be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore: So likewiſe he has laid down thoſe ſpecial Duties of the
Officers in the Church, who are to take the overſight, Feed, Govern, Go in
and out before them. <hi>Acts</hi> 20.17,18. 1. <hi>Pet.</hi> 5. and 2.</p>
            <p n="4">4. When the Church has had a Tryal of the meetneſs and
Abilities of any Perſon, or Perſons, for this work and ſervice, they are
by Election and Choice ſolemnly to ſet him, or them a part, by Prayer, and
Laying on of Hands. <hi>Acts</hi> 14.21,22,23. <hi>Acts</hi> 6. By which a new
relation ariſeth of an Elder, and a Church, a Paſtor, and a Flock: This
muſt be therefore by the mutual voluntary acts of each other, by which 
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:30333:12"/>the Duties of each relation becomes binding upon them,
according to the Laws of Chriſt: It is the Paſtors Duty now to Watch, Feed,
and Govern the Flock, and to give himſelf up to it; It is the Churches Duty
to ſubmit themſelves to Him in the Lord; to Love, Reverence, and
Adminiſter freely to him. 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 5.1,2,3,4,5. <hi>Heb.</hi> 13.7.17.
How greatly then muſt thoſe Churches be to blame, that un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>concernedly live
in the neglect of ſo great a Duty, upon which the Edifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation of the Church,
and her Well-being ſo much depends, as well as Goſpel Order: For although
the Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence and Being of a Church depends upon its Inſtitution in
reſpect both of Matter and Form: (A competent number of Believers may by
mutual agreement lay the Foundation of the Being of a Goſpel Church,) but
they cannot be a Church Organical with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Officers, which the Lord hath placed
there for the orderly Exerciſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> of
his Authority committed to her; To neglect this, is to deſpiſe the
Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom <pb n="10" facs="tcp:30333:13"/>of Chriſt, who beſt knows wha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> is for the good of His Church, and for
Her Edification in this State. 2, To ſlight His Goodneſs in ſo uſeful
and beneficial an Inſtitution. 3, Its a contempt put upon his Authority, as
King of Saints, who has in his Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign Right, in and over the Church,
Ordained it ſo to be, for the Churches Good and Well-being.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> As there ſhould not be a neglect of this
Duty, ſo there ſhould be great care taken that we an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer the Will of God
herein, wherein His Name and Honour is ſo much concerned, in Reſpect of his
Love to, and Care of his Church; therefore the greaeſt diligence ſhould be
taken that the Rules He has given be duly obſerved, and Applications made of
the Qualifications laid down, in reſpect of all ſuch that are called unto
Office: The outward Call is an Act of the Church, the<pb n="11" facs="tcp:30333:13"/>acceptation of the Perſon ſo called, is an Obediential Act of him
to the Will of God; but neither of theſe can be regular, where there is not
at previous indication of the Mind of God, in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtowing thoſe Spiritual
Gifts and Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications, as may render him com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petently fit to the
Diſcharge of his Office and Work.</p>
            <p>Now in a Churches undue proceeding herein, they diſcover their
own weak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, if not Ignorance, in reſpect of the Rule it ſelf, and
injure the Perſon ſo cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, in laying the weight of ſo great a Work
upon him, who is not furniſhed with Spiritual Abilities to diſcharge it,
&amp; thereby expoſe the Honour of Chriſt, and Reputation of His Goſpel
in the World, which ſhould be dear unto us.</p>
            <p>And we have reaſon to reckon that ſome Churches not walking
ſo regular herein, has been one cauſe of the want of that Reputation, which
otherwiſe they might have gained amongſt the Saints, and in the World,
obſerve what <hi>Moſes</hi> ſaid to <hi>Iſrael, Deut.</hi> 4.6.
<hi>Keep<pb n="12" facs="tcp:30333:14"/>therefore, and do them, for this is your Wiſdom
and your Underſtanding in the ſight of the Nations, which ſhall hear of
all theſe Statutes; and ſay, Surely this great Nation is a wiſe and
understanding People.</hi> Who otherwiſe were the leaſt of all Nations. We
ought with far greater reaſon to take heed we deviate not from the Laws of
the Son of God, who deſerves greater Honour than <hi>Moſes,</hi> which he
hath given to His Church, under the Goſpel Diſpenſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; If in the
choice of Deacons, <hi>Acts</hi> 6.3. They were to look out <hi>from amongst
themſelves Men of ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nest Report, full of the Holy Ghost and Wiſdom,</hi>
to be ſet apart to that Work: How much more in the choice of Paſtors or
Elders whoſe Work requires greater ſpiritual Abillities to a right
diſcharge thereof?</p>
            <p>For Churches therefore to be ſo uncon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd, whether they have
Officers or not, according to Goſpel Rule, or ſo overly in the Choice of
thoſe they ca<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> into ſuch high
ſtations amongſt them <pb n="13" facs="tcp:30333:14"/>whether they are competently
quali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied or not, are greatly blameable.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> In the next place we conclude, It is very
diſhonourable to God, and a reproach to our <hi>Sacred Religion</hi> for the
Churches when they have called forth ſuch Paſtors and Miniſters, who are
competently qualified accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Rule of the Goſpel, to let them lye
under thoſe unſupportable burdens, of worldly Snares and Incumbran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces,
without providing a due mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance for them, according to the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daination of
our Lord Jeſus Chriſt in the <hi>New Testament.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="section">
            <head>The Goſpel Miniſter's Maintenance Vindicated.</head>
            <p>AND indeed, it ſeems to us a thing Grievous as well as Strange,
that any People ſhould be ſo be clouded in their Underſtandings, as in
the leaſt<pb n="14" facs="tcp:30333:15"/>to doubt, whether it be Duty or no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that the Church ſhould allow a
Mee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and Due Maintenance, to their
Faith<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ful Paſtors and Teachers: Yet, w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> hear there are not only ſome who hav<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> doubts about it, but others, who ſee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to Object, and ſtiffly argue
againſt i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as if it were Unlawful,
if not Anti<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>chriſtian, for Miniſters to receive
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Yearly, or Quarterly Allowance
from the Churches, amongſt whom they are placed, and imployed as Labou<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rers;
which Conceit cannot be with<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>out its ſad Effects and Conſequences<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and
if they are not convinced o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> this
Miſtake and Error the ſooner may in a little time appear to the mor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> palpable Detriment, and Prejudice o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Goſpel, and Reproach of
Profeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, which is indeed too Viſible or Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt already;
therefore are we ſtir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red up in Love, to Chriſt and his Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed
Intereſt, and as a Prevention of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Evil and Danger threatned, upon th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Account of this Defect and Remiſne<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> of Duty, to Write this ſhort Treatiſe.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:30333:15"/>Our main Buſineſs at this time, is not
only to Aſſert the Miniſter's Maintenance to be an Inſtitution of
Chriſt; but alſo, to prove it ſo to be, and that to with-hold it from
them by a Church, who is able comfortably to provide for them, is a great and
cry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Sin, and will be attended (we fear unleſs prevented by an unfeigned
Repentance and Reformation) with ſevere Judgment from the Holy God, who will
not always bear with the Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norant, much leſs, the willful neglect of his own
Holy Law, contained ſo expreſly in his ſacred Word, and that we may do
this the more effectually, we ſhall in the firſt place cite thoſe
Scriptures, upon which we ground the Truth of what we Aſſert and Plead
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or.</p>
            <p>Matt. 10.9,10. <hi>Provide neither Gold,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>r Silver, nor Braſs in your
Purſes—<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>r Scrip for your
Journey, neither Two <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ats, neither
Shoes, nor Staves, for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ork-man
is Worthy of his Meat.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:30333:16"/>1 Tim. 5.17. <hi>Let the Elders who Rul<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> well be accounted worthy of double
Honor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> eſpecially they who labour
in the Word and Doctrine.</hi> For the Scripture ſaith, <hi>Thou ſhalt not
muzzle the Mouth of the Ox that treadeth cut the Corn, for the Labourer is
worthy of his Reward.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Gal. 6.6. <hi>Let him that is taught in the Word, communicate to
him that teach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth him in all good Things; be not deceived, God is not mecked,
for what a Man ſow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, that ſhall he reap.</hi> v. 7.</p>
            <p>1 Cor. 9.7. <hi>Who goeth a warfare at any time at his own Charge?
Who plant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Vineyard, and eaterh not of the Fruit thereof? Who feedeth a
Flock, and eat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth not of the Milk of the Flock?</hi> v. 9. <hi>Is it not
written in the Law of</hi> Moſes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>Thou ſhalt not muzzle the Mouth
of the Ox that treadeth out the Corn, doth God take Care for Oxen?</hi> v. 10.
<hi>Or ſaith <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> it altogether
for our ſakes? For ou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſakes no
doubt, this is Written, That h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> that
Ploweth, ſhall Plow in Hope; and he which Thraſheth in Hope, ſhall be
mad<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> partaker of his Hope.</hi> V.
11. <hi>If we hav<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:30333:16"/>Sown unto you Spiritual Things, is it a great Thing, if we
ſhall Reap your Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Things?</hi> v. 13. <hi>Do not you know, that they
which Miniſter about Holy Things, Live of the Things of the Temple; and they
that wait at the Altar, are partakers with the Altar.</hi> v. 14. <hi>Even ſo
hath the Lord ordained, that they which Preach
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Goſpel, ſhould live of the
Goſpel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>We will Appeal to all Mens Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciences in the Fear of God,
whether <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>here is any Duty lies more
clear and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>vident in expreſs Words
in the Holy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>cripture than this
doth; and yet how <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>trangly are
ſome good Chriſtians at a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oſs
about it, and are hardly brought <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o
receive it as an indiſpenſable Duty,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r elſe to a Faithful Diſcharge
of their Duty herein. Our Work is before us, we ſhall therefore proceed, to
open (as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Lord may help us,) the
Mind of God in theſe places of Holy Scripture,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd give you the Senſe of them.
Firſt, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>appears that as
ſoon as ever our bleſſed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aviour ſent forth his Miniſters to Preach
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Goſpel, as we have
ſhewed.</hi> Matt. 10.<pb n="18" facs="tcp:30333:17"/>7,8,9,10. <hi>He Diſcovered this
part of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Will and
Pleaſure.</hi> i. e. <hi>That they ſhou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> not ſpend, or waſte their own Subſtan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> they are forbid to take either Gold
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Silver, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which
Words clearly i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>timate, they might
have both Go<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Silver, and more
Coats, and Sho<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> too; but they were
not to take the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> with them, in their
Journey, bein<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſent forth to
Preach the Kingdom <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> God.</p>
            <p>Obj. <hi>But ſome poſſibly may Object
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> was but a temporary Precept,
being <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Will of God concerning
them, for that ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Journey at that
time.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We Anſwer, it ſeemeth to
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> manifeſtly to declare the
abſolute W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Pleaſure of
Chriſt, that his Fai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ful
Labourers ſhould be provided for the People with all things Neceſſar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> appertaining to this Life, and not of
then, but alſo, in all ſucceeding A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and we find our Worthy <hi>Annotators</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> directly agree with us herein,
th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> may be, ſome things contained
in th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> place might be temporary:
Take wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:30333:17"/>our
late <hi>Annotators</hi> ſay upon this Text, 
<note place="margin">Continuation of Mr. <hi>Poole</hi>'s
An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>notations.</note>
               <hi>Our Saviour deſigned to give them</hi> (ſaith he)
<hi>an Experience of the Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence of God, and to teach
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>em to truſt in it; as alſo, to
teach Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple that the Labourer is worthy of his hire, and that God expecteth,
that his Miniſters ſhould not live of their own, but upon the Alter,</hi> 1
<hi>which they ſerv'd; ſo as at once
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> taught his Diſciples not to
he Covetous, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> overmuch
Sollicitous, and the People <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
provide for thoſe who Miniſtred to them
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> things Spiritual.</hi>
Beſides thoſe other abſolute Precepts of like Nature, gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>en forth by the Spirit of Chriſt in
the Apoſtles, contained in ſeveral Epiſtles,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o ſufficiently prove this to be
the Mind <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd Intention of our
Saviour in this place</p>
            <p>Secondly, <hi>That we may put
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> out of all doubt, We ſhall
now come to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ſider of the
ſacred Appointment of God <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
this Matter:</hi> If it appear to be no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ing leſs, nor more, than what the
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ord has Ordained, <hi>viz.</hi>
That his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ervants who are called
forth to Preach <pb n="20" facs="tcp:30333:18"/>the Goſpel and take Care of his Churc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>es, ſhould have a fit and ſuitable
Ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tenance (according as the State
an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Ability of the Churches may be,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> whom they belong, and whoſe
Servan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> they are) than we hope there
is no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> will object or argue
againſt it any mor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>And that this is the Will, and Sacre<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Appointment of the Lord, is very ev<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dent in that fore-cited place. 1. <hi>Cor.</hi>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 14. and in divers others.
<hi>Even ſo ha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> the Lord ordained
that they that Prea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> the Goſpel,
ſhould live of the Goſpel.</hi> Tru<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the Lord hath not Ordained that
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Servants and Miniſters under
the G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſpel ſhould have Tythes,
or the Tent<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of every Members
increaſe, as he fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>merly
appointed under the Law; ye<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
nevertheleſs he hath taken Care of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and Ordained that they <hi>ſhould live of
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Goſpel,</hi> not (unleſs
Neceſſity requires<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that they
ſhould live on the <hi>Labor</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Hands, in common with other Me<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and pray obſerve, 'tis not ſaid
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Church has Ordained it, nor we
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Apoſtles have Ordained it;
but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:30333:18"/>Lord
hath Ordained it, or it is the Holy Appointment or Sacred Precept of Jeſus
Chriſt, for the Support and Comfort of his Painful and Faithful Servants; he
and his People have cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led forth to Preach his bleſſed Goſpel out ſome
may yet ſay, <hi>how has he Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> Pray obſerve, So hath the Lord Ordained, let us
look a little back, and take notice of the Scope and Coherence of the place;
the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtle hath a Reference to what preceeds, <hi>Do ye not know, that they
that Miniſter about Holy things, live of the things of the Temple; and they
which wait at the Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tar, are partakers with the Altar: So hath the Lord
Ordained,</hi> &amp;c. That is, as God had a Miniſtry under the Old
Teſtament. Namely, <hi>the Prieſt of the Tribe of</hi> Levi; and he
Ordained and Appointed a Comfortable Livelyhood
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> them, as <hi>Numb.</hi> 18.20.
<hi>Deut.</hi> 10. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and 18.1. So
as they needed not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Labor (as
other Men) with their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to get
Bread to eat; even ſo <pb n="22" facs="tcp:30333:19"/>hath the Lord Ordained and
appoint<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed, that thoſe who Preach the Goſpe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhould have likewiſe a Comfortabl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Livelyhood or Maintenance now un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der this
Diſpenſation, that they may be delivered from the Incumbrance<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of this Life, and ſo not hindred
o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> obſtructed in their Holy and
moſt Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cred Imployment, with ſecular Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs. <hi>God's Will</hi>
(ſaith our late <hi>Anno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tators</hi>) <hi>is the ſame, under the New
Teſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, that it was under the Old;</hi> i. e<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>It is not as to
the People a matter of Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty, ſo as they may chuſe whether they will
maintain their Miniſters or no, there is an Ordinance of God in the Caſe,
it is the Will of God, that thoſe who are taken off from Wordly Employments,
and ſpend their time in the Study, and Preaching the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpel ſhould have
a Livelyhood from their Labours.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This alſo agrees with what the ſame great Apoſtle ſaith,
Gal. 6.6. <hi>Let him that is taught in the Word, Communicate to him that
Teacheth in all good Things:</hi> Is not this think ye a Precept? Is not this
di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly<pb n="23" facs="tcp:30333:19"/>laid down, as other great and
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>diſpenſable Precepts and
Duties are, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>e Epheſ. 4.23.
<hi>Let him that ſtole, ſteal
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> more; but rather, let him
Labour with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>s Hands: Let no
corrupt Communicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> proceed out
of your Mouths,</hi> &amp;c. and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ain, <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 5.33.—<hi>Let every one of
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>u in particular ſo Love his
Wife,</hi> &amp;c. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ou can under no
pretence avoid theſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>eat Duties;
nor can you plead to be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>cuſed;
and pray doth not the ſame <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oly
Spirit, and ever bleſſed God, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>n and require you (in the ſame form
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Speech) who are taught in the
Word, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Communicate to him that
Teacheth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> all good Things. Shall
ſuch who <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ave always ſhewed much
Zeal for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>red Ordinances and
Inſtitutions of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>us Chriſt, and
plead for a Univerſal Obedience; juſtifie themſelves in the
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eglect of ſo plain a Precept,
Chriſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>h, <hi>then are ye my
Friends, if you do <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>atſoever I
have commanded you;</hi> pray <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
this great Ordinance then be thought
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>on, and have equal regard by you;
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Goſpel Inſtitution and
Appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment <pb n="24" facs="tcp:30333:20"/>of Jeſus Chriſt we argue fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>that ſo you may ſtand compleat
in t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> whole Will of God: You know
what</hi> Da<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vid ſaith, <hi>then I ſhall not be aſhamed whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> I have a reſpect to all thy
Commandments<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Let him that is taught in the Word, Com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>municate to him that
teacheth in all good things,</hi> that is, every one according a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> God hath bleſſed him with the good
things of this World; God would no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
have his Faithful Miniſters want any good thing to make their Lives
com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fortable to them;) if ſo be it be in the Power of thoſe who are taught
to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>municate it to them. <hi>The Precept</hi> (ſaith our late
<hi>Annotators</hi>) <hi>is concerning th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Maintenance of Miniſters, which is fit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> expreſſed by the</hi> Term
<hi>Communicate<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> becauſe, as the
People diſtribute to their Mi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>niſters things Temporal, ſo the Miniſters
diſtribute things Spiritual: The good things here mentioned are Temporal good
things ſuch as may be Uſeful to the Teacher for t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> uphold Himſelf and Family. The Tex<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> teacheth us, that it is the Will of God
tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Miniſters ſhould be
maintained at th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:30333:20"/>Charge of the Church, to which they Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter; and it is but an
Act of Juſtice, for they do but Communicate Temporal things, to thoſe who
Communicate to them much more valuable things:</hi> Be not de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, God is
not mocked, <hi>&amp;c. The</hi> Apoſtle <hi>addeth this</hi> (ſaith our
<hi>Annota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors</hi>) <hi>to terrify thoſe who find out vain and falſe
Excuſes to ſave their Purſes; he ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſeth them not to cheat
themſelves, for tho they might deceive Men, yet they could not deceive the
All-ſeeing, and Heart-ſearch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing God,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thirdly,</hi> But to proceed, <hi>Miniſters are commanded to
attend wholly, upon their Sacred Calling in their Miniſtry, and are required
not to contangle themſelves in the Affairs of this Life;</hi> for certainly,
what <hi>Paul</hi> willeth <hi>Timothy</hi> to do in this re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect, in him he
requireth all Miniſters <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o do the
like; and altho' every Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian in many reſpects may be compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to a
Souldier, yet in this place, 2 <hi>Tim.</hi> 2.4. The Apoſtle only aludes to
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hoſe in the Miniſtry, or ſuch
who are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>piritual Officers in
Chriſt's Army, they<pb n="26" facs="tcp:30333:21"/>ought to take heed who go forth i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that Warfare, they intangle not
them<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſelves with the affairs of this Life, <hi>i.
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> in Trades and Callings, which
othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Chriſtians are allowed to
follow: and the reaſon is offered <hi>that they may pleaſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> him who hath choſen them to be
Soldiers.</hi> And hence 'tis that the ſame Apoſtle in another place
exhorts <hi>Timothy,</hi> and ſo all other Miniſters (who the Church calls
forth to that great Work) to <hi>giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> himſelf up to Reading, to Exhortation, t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Doctrine, and to the Study of the Word<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Meditate on theſe things</hi>
(ſaith he) <hi>giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> thy
ſelf</hi> wholly <hi>to them,</hi> that they <hi>pro<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fiting may appear to
all.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Nothing, doubtleſs, but real neceſſity may diſpenſe with
the contrary, h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> whole time and
ſtrength is little e<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nough to be imployed in the Wor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Service he is called to. <hi>Let th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> things be the buſineſs of thy
Thoughts, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> take care of them, be
in them; ſo it is <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the</hi>
Greek (as our Annotators obſerv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <hi>Let them be thy whole Work.</hi> He m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſaith one, give himſelf up to the Min<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtry<pb n="27" facs="tcp:30333:21"/>of the Word
and Prayer, and continue in reading Meditation, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as a Man
wholly devoted unto Goſpel Service; and is therefore by his Call to the
Miniſtry ſecluded from thoſe ways and means of providing for his own
Subſiſtance, as Trades and Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Employments of others furniſh them
with; that his Mind by the cares of Wordly Buſineſs may not be diverted
from the Study of God's Word, and care of Souls, which the duty of his Station
engageth him to. And if he may not expoſe himſelf to the careful Thoughts
that accompany worldly Buſineſs, though tending to his Profit; certainly it
is no way meet that he ſhould be left to conflict with the Thorny Cares of a
neceſſitous Condition, whilſt thoſe he Miniſters
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o, have means to prevent it:
doubtleſs <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Holy God Ordained
the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ers Maintenance upon
moſt weighty Grounds and Reaſons; ſome of which,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>leſſed be His Name, he hath not
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oncealed or hid from us; and this 
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:30333:22"/>we ſay ſeem to us to be one among<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the reſt, <hi>viz. That his Mind and Thought<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> might not be diverted from his Work wit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Earthly Things.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Fourthly, <hi>And not in reſpect of himſelf upon this account
only, but alſo to prevent that occaſion of Scandal,</hi> that we ſee
daily is ready to attend Men who fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low Trades and Secular Employ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments in the
World; for let Chriſtiann Men be never ſo careful and circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect in
their Callings and Commerce with Men, we find by daily experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence how
ſubject they are to fall un<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>der the clamours of ſome ungodly and envious
People, they lying in wait fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> their
halting; and if it be a Miniſte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
or Paſtor of a Church that is a Tra<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ding Perſon, be ſure they will (if
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> be poſſible) watch him ſo
that he ſha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> not eſcape their
reproachful Tongu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> though it be not
in the leaſt deſerve<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and
hereby his Hands are not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly made
weak, but his Spirits a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> grieved,
and his Miniſtry made (th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
unjuſtly) contemptible. We find
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:30333:22"/>from hence
very neceſſary, that the Paſtors of our Churches, and Teachers too if
poſſible, ſhould be freed from all ſuch Inſnarements; and cannot but
obſerve the Wiſdom of God in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of His Holy Ordinance: <hi>i.
e.</hi> in ordaining a Support and Livelyhood for His Servants another way,
ſo that they might not be brought under In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>famy and Reproach; and that
thereby alſo the Word of God might the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Run and be Glorified. Theſe
two Arguments we cannot but Judge are weighty, namely; 1. the work of the
Miniſtry, eſpecially in the Hands of a Paſtor, being ſo great, that it
doth require his utmoſt attendance, or all his whole time and ſtrength, as
it muſt needs appear to every Man who ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berly and ſeriouſly
conſiders it in its Parts: 'Tis true a Man may bear that Name, and
Diſcharge that Sacred Office in part, nay, and as well as he can,
conſidering his circumſtances in the VVorld, and thereby have in part peace
in his Mind; but 'tis another<pb n="30" facs="tcp:30333:23"/>thing to diſcharge the duty
of this Ca<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing as he ought, and as
the <hi>Sanction</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Office
calls for, to the Honour of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
Holy Name of God, and Credit of Re<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ligion; for we conclude to Preach on<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> or two Sermons in a VVeek is the
leaſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> part of his Work, and the
leaſt indeed, if his Matter be not ſo well prepared and digeſted; that he
may <hi>ſhow himſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> a Workman
that needeth not be aſhame<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
rightly dividing the Word of Truth, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> ſo every one may have their portion
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Meat in due Seaſon;</hi>
which that <hi>Tim<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>thy</hi> might
do, St. <hi>Paul</hi> adviſes him to a careful and diligent Study: But how
ſuch poor Men can do this, who a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
forc'd to follow their Trades hard e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ry Day in the Week, to get Bread for their Families, we ſee not?
But be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſides the great VVork of giving them<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſelves up to Reading,
Meditation, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> laborious and
diligent Study an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Preaching of
God's VVord. There <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> another
great Duty lyes upon the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> which is,
Viſiting the Members of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
Church under their Care, ſo that th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:30333:23"/>may <hi>know the State of their Flock;</hi>
yea' go from Houſe to Houſe: And if this be not done, How can they ſo
well know what Food to Adminiſter or Hand forth unto ſome poor Souls they
have committed to their Charge? VVhere the VVork of Viſiting is ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glected,
we conclude one main Part of the Paſtors Buſineſs lies undone; and what
an account they will have to give of the Souls of Men and VVomen to Jeſus
Chriſt, We know not, if they be remiſs here: or what an account the Church
can give if they are out of a capacity to diſcharge this great Truſt,
through neglect of their Duty to them. <hi>They</hi> (ſaith the Apoſtle)
<hi>Watch for your Souls, as ſuch as muſt give account.</hi> Heb. 13.17.
And then Secondly, the Credit and Honour of their Miniſtry, in reſpect of
what we before mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, ought to be conſidered; for if the Preacher hath
Blots and Stains upon him, through the neceſſities he may be in, in
reſpect of the things of this VVorld, by not having his wants ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed, 
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:30333:24"/>but is involved in Debt, or ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed to the breach of his
VVord in the way of Trading. VVhat weight or power think you, will his
Miniſtry have upon the Conſciences of Men? For it neceſſarily makes
room for the old Proverb, <hi>Phyſician heal thy ſelf;</hi> and it is as a
prevention of thoſe Evils, <hi>i. e.</hi> for the good, Health, and
VVell-being of the Souls both of Paſtors and Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple here and hereafter. VVe
conclude, that God has been pleaſed to Ordain and ſo to provide for his
Servants in the Miniſtry, as we have ſhewed; but this is not all; For</p>
            <p>Fifthly, <hi>According to the Law and Light of Nature, the Church
is obliged to provide for their Miniſters,</hi> as to the matter of Equity
and Juſtice; and from hence the Apoſtle argues the Point with the
<hi>Corinthians<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 9.7. &amp;c. <hi>Who goeth a
Warfa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> at any time at his own
Charge? Wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Planteth a Vineyard,
and eateth not of the Fruit thereof? Or who Feedeth
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Flock, and eateth not of the
Milk of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Flock.</hi> None that
Liſts an Army, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pects<pb n="33" facs="tcp:30333:24"/>that his Souldiers ſhould
main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain themſelves without Pay: The Miniſtry is a Spiritual Warfare,
un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertaken at the Command of Chriſt, and by the Call of the Church for the
ſervice of their Souls; and 'tis as rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable that Miniſters ſhould
receive a ſupply of outward things from them as that a Soldier ſhould
receive Pay from his Captain at the charge of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Common-wealth, for whoſe Good and Safety he enters
upon that Mili<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tary Employment. Again the Apo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtle argues the equitableneſs
of it fur<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ther; <hi>Shall a Man Plant a Vineyard an not Eat of the Fruit
thereof?</hi> The Preach<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing the Goſpel is like a man planting
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Vineyard; the Church is compared
thereto in Scripture, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 5.1.2. Th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Plants are the Lords, but he uſeth Mi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>niſters Hands in the
Planting of them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and none planteth a Vineyard but
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> expectation of ſome Fruit
from thenc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> none Imployeth his
Servant to Plant, but he doth (and 'tis but luſt he ſhould) uphold him with
Food and <pb n="34" facs="tcp:30333:25"/>Raiment, he doing his Work. The Church alſo, as
the Apoſtle intimates, is compared to a Flock; And now who Feedeth a Flock,
either perſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally, or by his Servants, but he eateth, or alloweth his
Servant to eat of the Milk of the Flock, which it is his VVork to keep and
feed? By theſe three Inſtances commonly known to Men, the Apoſtle
ſheweth the rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonableneſs that the Miniſters of the Goſpel ſhould
be maintained by the People to whom they Miniſter; he plainly intimating that
it is inconſiſtent with common Juſtice to deprive a man of the Fruit of
that Vineyard which is planted and manured by his own Labour. And ſuch is the
caſe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween a Miniſter and his People; it is not (as one well obſerves)
your Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity that we ask for them, but Juſtice and Right, which the very
Light of Nature as well as God's Word clearly ſheweth: They are Imployed in
your Service, and do that Buſineſs for you in which your Eternal
Happineſs is<pb n="35" facs="tcp:30333:25"/>concerned; they take care to provide Bread
for your Souls, and of right therefore ſhould live upon your charge, and you
ought to ſee that neither they, nor their Families want Bread, nor a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing
neceſſary for their Bodies: Nay, and ſince <hi>they Sow or Import unto
you Spiritual Things, Is it a great thing if they ſhall reap your carnal
things?</hi> Have you not (as if the Apoſtle ſhould ſay) better things
from them, than they partake of from you? St. <hi>Paul</hi> (as our Annotators
note) argueth the reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ableneſs <hi>of Miniſters maintenance from their
People, they giving them</hi> quid pro quo, <hi>a juſt Compenſation for
ſuch allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, yea that which is of much more value; for there is a great
diſproportion between things Spiritual and things Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal; the former much
excelling the latter, ſo that the People have the advantage, they receiving
things far more excellent from Chriſt's Miniſters, than his Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters
receive of them:</hi> They communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate Gold and precious Stones, and Pearl;
and do receive from the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple<pb n="36" facs="tcp:30333:26"/>that which comparatively is
bu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as Braſs or Copper; And yet
ſhall this ſeem a great thing? Will you, as if the Apoſtle ſhould
ſay, Grudge them a due portion of your Temporals, when you receive ſo
plentifully from them of choice Heavenly or Spiritual things? How
unreaſonable a thing is this?</p>
            <p>Obj. <hi>But ſome may be will Object the things they
communicate,</hi> viz. <hi>thoſe Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Things, are not their own but the
Lords, and imparted to them to hand out for the good of others;</hi> And
therefore the Caſe is different.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> It is againſt the Apoſtle you raiſe this
<hi>Objection:</hi> But will you ſee how you are miſtaken? Pray what more
Right or Property have you to your Carnal Things, than they have to their
Spirituals? Are not their Spiritual Things their own, as much as your Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal
Things are your own? Hath the Lord made you any other than Stew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards 
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:30333:26"/>of your worldly Things; And muſt not you be Accountable
to him for them, if you do not lay them out as he hath Commanded you? For the
good of others come your Carnal Things, even <hi>your Wooll and your Flax.</hi>
Hoſ. 2.9. is as much the Lords, as the Miniſters. Knowledg, and other
Spiritual Gifts are the Lords; and it doth as much behove you to ſee that you
Communicate to others of your VVorldly or Carnal Things: VVe mean to the Poor
Saints and Miniſters of the Goſpel, as it behoveth them to Preach or
Communicate Spiritual Things to you; and therefore the Caſe is not different:
Beſides, you forget how your poor Miniſters oft times waſt their
ſtrength, and conſume their Bodies, being brought to utter Weak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in
their outward Man, in their painful Studies and Labours, in Preaching the Word,
thereby Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicating Spiritual Things to you: And is not that (we mean health
<hi>&amp;c.</hi>) more in worth (and their own too)<pb n="38" facs="tcp:30333:27"/>than all
you have or can Communi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cate to them? Sure their ſtrength, and the health of
their Bodies together with the expence of their Time, you will ſay, is as
much their own, as any thing you can call yours; And is
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> then a great thing they
ſhould be ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed from you with all things neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary for this Life?
Beſides, in point o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Equity our
Saviour as well as the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtle calls Miniſters Labourers; and you all will
readily ſay, <hi>The Labourer is worthy of his Hire.</hi> How then is it
tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> any ſhould ſeek ways, and
excuſes to avoid their Duty herein to their Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Harveſt Men? we
muſt tell yo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> again, tis Jeſus
Chriſt who ſaith tis thei<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> due,
and that they are worthy of it<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and He hath Ordained that they ſhould
have it; ſo that you cannot with h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> it from them without Sin, nay ſuch
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Sin that is not only againſt
the Law and Light of Nature, but the expreſs Law of Jeſus Chriſt: And we
muſt tel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> you, That if the keeping
back, or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frauding the Hire of your Labourers, <pb n="39" facs="tcp:30333:27"/>who have
Reaped down your Corn Fields, be ſo great an Evil, that their Cry enters into
the Ears of the Lord of Sabbaths, and doth provoke and ſtir up the juſtice
of God to a ſevere Vengeance, for their daring Boldneſs and cruel
Oppreſſion of the poor: VVhat think you will be the Effects of the Cry of
Chriſts painful Spiritu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Harveſt-men, who Labour to gather in his Divine
Corn, ſhould you with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold from them their juſt Right upon this Account; by
which means they may be expoſed, eſpecially ſome of them, to Heart
Diſquieting, and Soul Afflicting Snares in the World, and their poor Families
want ſuch things as are neceſſary for them, when it is in the power of
the Peoples hands plentifully to ſupply them: We muſt in diſcharge of our
Duty at this time be plain with every Man, that we may deliver our own Souls
and theirs too, from ſo great a Sin as ſuch an neglect as that is does
appear to us to be, and will to all, if ſeriouſly Conſider'd, and laid to
Heart.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:30333:28"/>Object. <hi>May be ſome will Object ou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Miniſters do not need it, nor
deſire it of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> they can live
without it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> So perhaps ſome <hi>of your Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veſt-men that
Reap down your Fields,</hi> may be well to paſs in the World, and can live
without their Hire and Juſt due <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Yet will that be a good Plea
(think you) to ſeek ways or means to with-hold their wages from them? So, and
in like manner ſay we, the Ability of your paſtors in reſpect of the
things of the World, doth not excuſe you from the diſcharge of your Duty to
them, according to the Juſt Law of God, and Equitableneſs of the Caſe.
Yet certainly they (if of <hi>Paul</hi>'s Spirit) will refuſe to receive any
thing leſt it ſhould leſſen their eſteem in their Miniſtry; tis
left to their Liberty, they may chuſe whether they will receive it or not:
But though they may diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence with their Right if they pleaſe as
<hi>Paul</hi> did ſometimes through<pb n="41" facs="tcp:30333:28"/>his great Zeal and
Love to the Goſpel; yet cannot you diſpence with your Duty, you have no
War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant ſo to do: Yet we can't but greatly commend thoſe Paſtors of the
Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>es, who can and do without re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiving any thing, ſerve Chriſt and
his People, and reſolve (being Bleſſed with the good things of the world)
not to make the Goſpel Chargeable, or a Burden to any; but yet we would have
you ſenſible of your Duty, and look upon your ſelves to be Debtors to
them, and eſteem of them the more: But do theſe Paſtors who are Rich,
Able, and VVilling to ſerve the Churches for nothing, ſequeſter or give
themſelves up to the VVork of the Miniſtry, and faithfully diſcharge that
Truſt, as another who is taken off of Secular Employment? But may be, though
they are like other <hi>Labourers,</hi> yet if they did receive it from you,
they could Diſtribute it to the Needy, or to help other poor Miniſters who
ſerve other Churches, whoſe Poverty may<pb n="42" facs="tcp:30333:29"/>be ſuch, that
they cannot allow a ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cient Maintenance to their Paſtors And therefore
whether it may be neceſſary for you to with hold it from them, or for them
to refuſe it, is worth Conſideration.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Sixthly.</hi> But to proceed. <hi>(Since we are pleading the
Caſe in point of Equity and juſt Right, let it be Conſidered:) You do not
chuſe ſuch Men to be your Paſtors, or Miniſters, who are of the
loweſt of the People;</hi> but ſuch as may be allowed to have aſhare of
Parts, Common Pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, and Abilitys for Buſineſs with other Perſons:
and ſome of them could manage Trades, or fall into other Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployments, and
get Eſtates as well as you, if they were not Devoted to a better Service: And
muſt (as one obſerv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth) they needs be devoted to Neceſſities and
Miſeries, in the ſame Hour that they enter upon the Miniſtry. This ought
not to be; GOD hath Ordered the Caſe otherwiſe in his VViſdom, Certainly
(all will Confeſs) tis the<pb n="43" facs="tcp:30333:29"/>Duty of a Miniſter, as well
as other Men to provide for his Family, as much as lies in him; or take Care of
his VVife and Children that they may not be expoſed to a Thouſand
Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeries and Temptations when he is gone: For though a Covetous raking
Temper, worſe becomes a Miniſter of all Men in the VVorld (yet as the
Author before cited Noteth) we greatly miſtake our ſelves to think he
muſt diveſt himſelf of that due Affection of an Husband to his VVife, or
of a Father toward his Children; or that thoſe Fruits thereof which are
Juſtly eſteemed Commendable in others, ſhould be thought in him to be a
Fault: And is it not ſad (Judge you) That they muſt be conſtrained to one
of theſe <hi>Dialema's? i. e.</hi> Either to neglect the full and Faithfull
Diſcharge of their Duty to Chriſt and his Church, or elſe Neglect their
poor Families by fulfilling their Miniſtry, and doing the work of Paſtors,
according to the Nature of that Sacred Office. But as<pb n="44" facs="tcp:30333:30"/>to him
who is poor (and muſt ge<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his
Bread before he Eats it) wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> thinks
he can Diſcharge both theſe Duties well enough, tis to be feared he does
never a one of them as he ought Moreover, 'tis good for him to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider the
reaſon of that Law of the ever Bleſſed God, who hath otherwiſe
Ordained. Yet let every Servant of Chriſt uſe his own Freedom, and act and
do, as he thinks may moſt promote the Glory of God, and Good of the Church,
and the Increaſe thereof; ſo that he may give a good account of himſelf
in the Day of Chriſt.</p>
            <p>Seventhly, <hi>The Lord hath not left me To argue this only from
general Principles of Reaſon, and common Equity, but to put the Matter beyond
diſpute</hi> (as we have already ſhewed) hath ſubjoyned <hi>His expreſs
Command.</hi> And may not <hi>in the next place, that Proviſion which God was
pleaſed to make for his Miniſters in the time of the Law,</hi> be of great
uſe to us, and full of Inſtruction upon this ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count? Nay, and ought we
not to<pb n="45" facs="tcp:30333:30"/>conſider it, ſith the Apoſtle argueth 1.
<hi>Cor</hi> 9.13. for a Goſpel Maintenance from thence. <hi>Do ye not know,
that they which Miniſter about Holy things, live of the Things of the Temple;
and they which ſerve at the Altar, are par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers with the Altar?</hi> It
appears this is a Duty ſtill; and tho' the mode or manner of the Maintenance
of the Miniſters of God under the Law, was quite different to this under the
Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel, yet the reaſon and equitableneſs of the thing abides:
Miniſters were then provided for by the Lord; ſo he has ordered they
ſhould Live com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortably now under the Goſpel. We find God did then no
ſooner ſeparate the <hi>Levites</hi> to the Service of the Sanctuary, but
he by Law provided for their Subſiſtence: And though they were but one
Tribe in Twelve, yet the <hi>Tenth</hi> of the Increaſe of the whole Land was
given to them, beſides the firſt Fruits and Offerings, and diverſe other
Advantages; ſo that their Lot and Portion might equal, yea exceed 
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:30333:31"/>that of their Brethrens. This indeed is Abrogated; Goſpel
Miniſters have no Divine Right to the <hi>Tenths</hi> of men Increaſe; but
the Moral Equity we ſay does not ceaſe; nor can it be thought to be any
Burden to provide a comfortable Livelyhood for our Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters, were but our
Senſes rightly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſed to diſcern how Good and Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious God appears
to us under the Goſpel Diſpenſation, in eaſing our People from thoſe
vaſt and great Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence and Charges which the Lord's People were required to
be at under the Law: For we ſhall ſoon perceive, if we conſider, that the
charge of the Worſhip of God, and the Miniſtry, &amp;c. now is
comparitively little or no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, to what there was under that
Diſpenſation; though Men did en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour now to come up to their duty for as
one obſerves, he thought he could make it appear, <hi>That the Fifth Part of
their Eſtates was Yearly to be Spent in Things relating to Temple
Service.</hi> And we know not but he might ſay<pb n="47" facs="tcp:30333:31"/>right: And
yet we cannot be unſenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of the excellency of the Goſpel Miniſtry,
above the Miniſtry, of the Law; And what great Bleſſings and Priviledges
upon many Accounts we have above them? One would think theſe things were
enough to ſtir up all Faithful Chriſtians to leave their Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putings, and
heartily with a cheerful Mind be ready to contribute towards the defraying the
moderate Charge of a Goſpel Miniſtry, in ſuch a manner as may give
Reputation to our Sacred Profeſſion; certainly the Labourer is ſtill
worthy of his Hire; and every one will ſay, not leſs worthy becauſe he
Labours under the Goſpel, than they who Laboured under the Law.</p>
            <p>Eighthly, <hi>An Elder, or a Paſtor of a Church, is under a
ſpecial Charge to Uſe Hoſpitality, and to let himſelf be a Pattern of
Charity, and other good Works,</hi> that ſo he may the better adorn his
Profeſſion. This is his Duty, and if he fails herein, he loſes ſome
part of thoſe moſt excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Virtues in which he ought to 
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:30333:32"/>ſhine: but if he be Poor, and left
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the thorny cares of this World,
and the Church not adminiſtring ſo to him,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to put him into a Capacity to
anſwe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> this requirement of the
Goſpel, whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> will the fault and
blame lie? Therefore<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſince he ought to be a patern of Hoſpi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tality
and Charity; we argue, 'tis doubt<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>leſs the indiſpenſible Duty of the
Peo<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ple to whom he Miniſters, to be conce<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ned to the uttermoſt of their Abilities to make him capable of
giving Proof <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this Grace, by the
Exerciſe of it as the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> may be
Occaſion.</p>
            <p>Ninthly, <hi>We alſo argue for this Duty from the
Conſideration of the Honourable<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>neſs of it, when 'tis faithfully
diſcharged<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> it being one of thoſe things, which
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Honeſt, Juſt, Pure,
Lovely,</hi> and of <hi>g<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
Report,</hi> there is both <hi>Vertue</hi> and <hi>Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> attends it, <hi>Phil.</hi> 4.8. Firſt of all,
Ho<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> can Men think you are the People
yo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> profeſs your ſelves to be,
<hi>viz.</hi> Such w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> endeavour to
VValk Blameleſsly, i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> obſerving
all the Ordinances an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Commandments
of the Lord Jeſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:30333:32"/>whilſt you neglect this ſo plain and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deniable an
Inſtitution, even ſuch a one, that 'tis expreſly ſaid, <hi>So God hath
Ordained it,</hi> &amp;c. VVhy are you ſo Zea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous for ſome other Precepts
and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſs here? Doth not the ſame God who commandeth you to Repent, to
Believe, and to be Baptiz'd, and to Love one another; command you al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo to
Communicate to your Miniſters in all good things? How is it then? that any
can be ſo partial in the Law of Jeſus Chriſt.</p>
            <p n="2">2. This will in a great meaſure de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>iver you from that reproach of Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vetouſneſs: What
can any People <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hink ſhould be the
cauſe why Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ns ſhould
ſuffer their Miniſters to want what is neceſſary for them, when
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hey themſelves are ſo full?
Unleſs it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e from the Spirit of
this World; which is a Sin too often laid at the
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oors of the Profeſſors of this
Age: Would to God there was no cauſe or
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>round for it.</p>
            <p n="3">
               <pb n="50" facs="tcp:30333:33"/>3. Hereby the People will alſo rai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the Reputation and Honour of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Miniſtry, and ſhew their great
eſtee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of them, which well agrees
with th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Exhortation of the
Apoſtle; <hi>Let t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> Elders that
Rule well be accounted w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> thy of
double Honour, eſpecially they w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
Labour in the Word and Doctrine. F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
the Scripture ſaith, Thou ſhalt not M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> the Mouth of the Oxe that treadeth
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the Corn: For the Labourer is
worthy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> his Reward.</hi> 1 Tim.
17.18.</p>
            <p>By double Honour here is mean<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as ſome conclude, <hi>Reverence or H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nourable Eſteem</hi> for Chriſt's
Sake<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> whoſe Ambaſſadors they
are ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> be, and ſo
repreſent His Moſt Sacre<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
Majeſty.</p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>Maintenance.</hi> And 'tis evide<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> this cannot be excluded in this plac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> conſidering the Connextion of t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Words following; for the ScriptU<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſaith, <hi>Thou ſhalt not muzzle
the O<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> that Treadeth out the Corn,
and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Labourer is worthy of his
Reward.</hi> T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Verſe, ſaith
our <hi>Annotators,</hi> maketh<pb n="51" facs="tcp:30333:33"/>evident, <hi>That
Maintenance is part of the double Honour that is due to ſuch as Labour in the
Word and Doctrine.</hi> This then muſt be granted it tends to the Honour of
Chriſt's Miniſters; but 'tis as evident to all, that thoſe Perſons, let
them be of what Perſwaſion ſoever, if they ſhould leave their
Miniſters to the wide World to ſhift for them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, and though Poor,
take no care of them; inſtead of honouring of them, they would caſt a
ſlight and contempt upon them: and hence 'tis that others alſo for their
following of ſome Trades, do lay them under great re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proach, which the
Churches to whom they belong, if able, might and oug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to deliver them from. We are per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded there are
ſome rich Members <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> moſt
Congregations, that would not indure that any of their near Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations ſhould
fall under ſuch, or the like Circumſtances, or be expoſed to ſuch
Inconveniencies, becauſe of the diſhonour they Judge it would be to
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>em; People knowing they are 
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:30333:34"/>Wealthy and Great in the World, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> able to do conſiderable for ſuch nea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Kindred, or elſe all would ſay they
have no favour nor eſteem for them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> And ſhall Men ſhew greater
favou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and reſpect to their Carnal
Relations, than to Chriſt's Ambaſſadors? Thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſurely ought not to be.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Tenthly,</hi> Further to Evince thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> great Duty, <hi>It may not be amiſs to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider of
other great Inconveniences that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
fellow the neglect of it.</hi> There are ſom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Miniſters in the Churches who wer<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> brought up to Learning, and who ar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> utterly uncapable to follow Secula<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Trades and Callings: now if Provi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſion be not made for theſe
Me<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> What will become of them? How
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> it poſſible they and their
Famili<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> ſhould Live? Beſides,
What Inco<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ragement is here given to
others wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> are Young, whom God hath
Grac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ouſly indowed with
conſiderable Gif<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and are willing
to give up themſelv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to the
Miniſtry? And for their bette<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
Accompliſhment endeavour after th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:30333:34"/>Knowledg of the Tongues, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which we all
confeſs is very good and ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viceable, though not of abſolute
ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity in a Miniſter: Who will apply himſelf (we ſay) to gather,
and lay up thoſe ſtores of ſolid Learning, which oft-times in the Defence
of the Truth againſt Oppoſers, has been found very profitable, when he can
expect nothing but Poverty and Diſtreſs thereby: Nay furthermore, may not
this neglect quite deter any Godly Young Men to exerciſe their Gifts, in
order to ſerve the Churches in after times, when Death ſhall call away
thoſe Labourers the Churches have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ow amongſt them, ſhould they ſee
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he preſent Miniſtry ſlighted,
and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ot provided for: Or what ground
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ave we to expect a Bleſſing by
the Providence of God, to attend the Churches in reſpect of an Able and
Honourable Miniſtry in time to come, when His great Ordinance is ſlighted
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd neglected, which He in Wiſdom
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ath Ordained for an Encouragement
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:30333:35"/>upon this very account. In his own Way we may look for a
Bleſſing, bu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> not out of it.</p>
            <p>Nay to be plain with you, Have not ſome in a few Years laſt
paſt ſee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to their great trouble
and grief, how this neglect and ommiſſion of Duty hath laid (divers hopeful
young Men who were indued with excellent Gift for the Miniſtry) under great
Temp<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tations, even ſo far as to refuſe utterly the exerciſe of their
Gifts to the Prof<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Edification
of the Churches; lea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> in proceſs
of time they ſhould be cal<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>led forth to a Paſtoral Charge, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> thereby be expoſed to Snares and
Po<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>verty in the World; as perhaps ſom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> poor Miniſters and Paſtors have been, and may be daily ſtill
are; eſpecially they conſidering and laying to Heart the Care and Charge
their Paren<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> have been at with them,
in putting them forth to good Trades and Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, whereby they knew with
th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Bleſſing of God they might
(if they gave themſelves up with a due and ne<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ceſſary<pb n="55" facs="tcp:30333:35"/>Diligence and Induſtry to fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ow thoſe Trades) live well in the World, and ſufficiently
provide for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hemſelves (and their
Wives and Children, if they ſaw good to Marry)
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n after-times? And by this very
means <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Churches (may be to their
great <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oſs and detriment) have
been depri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved of thoſe great helps which a faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful diſcharge of Duty to
the preſent Miniſtry, may prevent for time to
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ome. Alſo, do we not ſee at
this very time what a ſad paſs ſome Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gregations are come to already,
for want of uſeful helps in the Miniſtry, both in City and Country; ſome
Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtors (nay many of them) being grown very Ancient, and almoſt become
un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerviceable, and not like to continue
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ong: And though the Harveſt is
great, yet O! how few are the Labourers a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt us, and fewer they are like
to be, if care be not taken in the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge of this indiſpenſible Duty
to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he preſent Miniſtry: Nor is
it a ſtrange thing that Godly Men ſhould <pb n="56" facs="tcp:30333:36"/>fall under
ſuch a Temptation which we before mentioned, conſidering this great Evil
and neglect of Duty herein: Since we find of Old in the <hi>Holy
Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture</hi> the very ſame Snare and Tempta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion many of the Prieſts and
Miniſters of the Lord fell under. Pray read and carefully conſider
<hi>Nehemiah</hi> 13.8,9. eſpecially the 10 Verſe. <hi>And I per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived
that the Portions of the Levites had not been given them; For the Levites and
the Singers that did the Work, were Fled every one to his Field.</hi> Now 'tis
evident that through the like Evil and Neglect of the People to the Levites and
Miniſters of God, in not giving them that due allowanee or mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance God
had Ordained for them, they left their work and ſervice every one of them,
and betook themſelves to ſecular Employments, <hi>viz.</hi> to labour in
the Fields and manure their Land, or gather in their Corn, which ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to
the <hi>Law</hi> others were to do for them. Nor did <hi>good Nehemiah</hi> (as
we can find) reprove or blame the <hi>Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vites</hi> 
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:30333:36"/>for
ſo doing: Nor indeed, what reaſon was there he ſhould? conſider<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
'tis a Moral Duty for every Man to provide for himſelf and Family; and he
that does not do it, the Apoſtle ſhews <hi>is worſe than an Infidel, and
hath denyed the Faith.</hi> But he contended ſharply with the People,
eſpecially with the Rulers; ſaying, <hi>Why is the Houſe of God
forſaken?</hi> That is, the Work of the Houſe of the Lord. <hi>And he
gathered them together, and ſet them in their place.</hi> verſe 11. They
had not only injured the <hi>Levites,</hi> as our <hi>Anno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tators</hi>
obſerve upon the place, in with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holding their Dues, but alſo occaſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
the neglect of GOD's Houſe and Service, <hi>&amp;c. And he gathered them
to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether:</hi> That is, ſay they, from their ſeveral Poſſeſſions
in the Country, in which they were diſperſed, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtored them to the
Exerciſe of their Office. And <hi>Then,</hi> ſaith the Text, <hi>brought
all</hi> Judah <hi>the Tithe of the Corn, and the new Wine, and the Oyl unto
the Treaſuries.</hi> Verſe 12. We cannot <pb n="58" facs="tcp:30333:37"/>ſlightly
paſs by this matter, for the Evil and Danger of the Sin of the Churches upon
this account, doth as palpably appear in this Caſe, as in any we have
mentioned. How can we expect in ordinary way to have an Able
<hi>Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry</hi> raiſed up; or thoſe who are now imployed in the Work
of the Goſpel carry on that Work, to the Honour of GOD, Comfort of His
People, and to the Credit of our Sacred Religion, if a Goſpel Incouragement
be not given them? True, we may perhaps have Preachers; ſome may be willing
to Exerciſe their Gifts, but is it fit think you, to call ſuch to Preach
pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lickly, who have ſcarcely one Hours time to prepare themſelves for the
Work; or may be have not meet and proper Indowments or Qualifications for that
Holy and Sublime Service. What is it (Judge you) that cauſes the Miniſtry
to be ſlighted and neglected in ſome places, but the want of ſuch a
<hi>Miniſtry</hi> that may honourably carry it on? And who ſhall we blame?
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:30333:37"/>What would you have poor men to do, that have (may be) no
time to ſpare to give themſelves up to the Stu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of the Scriptures, nor no
uſeful Books and proper helps to improve and aſſiſt them in their
Study: or if they have, yet their circumſtances in the World will not afford
them ſo much leiſure from their worldly Buſineſs, to read and meditate
upon the Word, ſo as well to digeſt what they have to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver to the
People. Come, think and ſay what you pleaſe; 'tis not without diligent and
continued Study, that the deep things of God can be ſearched out, and ſo
propoſed, as to inrich the minds of people with clear and ſolid Knowledge:
He that is not indowed with the clear Light and Underſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Divine
Truths, or the myſtery of the Goſpel himſelf, How can he Feed others as
they ought to be Fed with the Knowledg of thoſe Sublime and Soul inriching
<hi>Myſteries?</hi> A little Knowledg and Study 'tis true (as one obſerves)
may furniſh a man with<pb n="60" facs="tcp:30333:38"/>ſuch a Diſcourſe, as may
pleaſe ſome weak Chriſtians that Judg of a Sermon by the loudneſs of
the Voice and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectionate Sentences, or can fancy themſelves to be Fed with
good Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine, when perhaps 'tis but with the Aſhes of Jingling Words and
cadency of Terms. But alas! (ſaith he) the ſeeming warmth of Affection that
is ſtirred up by ſuch means, is as ſhort Liv'd as a Land Flood that hath
no Spring to Feed it. He that will do the Souls of his people good, and
ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove himſelf a Paſtor after God's own Heart, muſt endeavour to Feed
them with Knowledg and Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, that the people may learn and come to
underſtand thoſe things which were hid, and not opened or known to them
before; and ſo ſtrive to maintain a conſtant Zeal and Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection in them,
by well informing their Judgments, and ſuch an opening of the mind of God
from the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, as may command their Conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ences. And this is not to
be expected,<pb n="61" facs="tcp:30333:38"/>but from him that Labours in his Stu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, as
well as in the Pulpit: But ſaith he) miſtake me not; we know
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he ſucceſs and fruit of all
Studies and Labours of men that preach the Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel, is from the Grace and
Power of the Holy Ghoſt, but the aſſiſtance of the Spirit is to be
expected by the uſe of means, and in the way of our Duty. And now from the
whole, this is that we ſay, 'Tis not to be thought men can arrive to that
degree of Light and Knowledg in the deep things of God, and myſtery of
Chriſt, ſo as to preach the Goſpel as they ought, unleſs they dedicate
and give themſelves up by <hi>Prayer</hi> and <hi>Meditation</hi> to the
dilligent ſearch and Study of the Word of GOD, which cannot be done unleſs
ſome time be ſpent, which divers men cannot ſpare without a due Allowance
for their pains and loſs of time. And this we ſay too, is nothing leſs
nor more than what God has Ordained and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly Appointed in this
<hi>Matter</hi> in the<pb n="62" facs="tcp:30333:39"/>
               <hi>New Teſtament,</hi> as we have
ſufficiently proved: But to proceed,</p>
            <p>Eleventhly, <hi>The great Duty of the People to contribute towards
the publick Worſhip of God, and the Miniſtry may be further demonſtrated
and the Evil and Sin in their neglect of it evinc'd, from the Conſideration
of that ſharp reproof, and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Judgments of God, brought againſt, and
denounced upon the People of Old,</hi> upon this very account, ſo
<hi>Mal.</hi> 3.8. <hi>Will a Man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me:</hi> The evil
of this Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple lay in this, <hi>i. e.</hi> In that they did not faithfully
bring into his Houſe all thoſe Riches and good Things, which by the Law and
Requirement of God they ought to have done, for the carrying on and management
of the Service of the Temple, and publick VVorſhip of God; they through
Covetouſneſs, or a baſe Carnal and Self-ſeeking Spirit, did retain and
keep back part of theſe Tythes and Offerings for their own Uſe, or to
inrich themſelves, and did not yield them up to the Uſe and End 
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:30333:39"/>God had appointed them: And this the People might do,
<hi>i. e.</hi> rob God, <hi>viz.</hi> in with-holding from the Prieſts of the
Lord what was appointed or ordained for them: And alſo this the Prieſts
might do, whilſt they took too much, and more than what was their due
Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance, or take the VVages, and not do the VVork which was appointed for
them. However, to keep back, or retain part, or the whole, of what God has
ordained and commanded to be brought into his Houſe, for the carrying on, and
well Management of his pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick VVorſhip, <hi>The Lord calls it a robbing of
him:</hi> And certainly God hath as great Care, and has made as Honourable
Proviſion for the Goſpel Church, and his VVorſhip and Intereſt now,
under this Diſpenſation, as he had then; and has appointed or ordain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
that his People bring into his Houſe now, ſo that nothing may be wanting
for the Honourable management and carrying on the VVork of the Goſpel, and
the Miniſtration therefore, in any<pb n="64" facs="tcp:30333:40"/>Reſpect: Nor can this
be done with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Charge; And if the Lords Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple ſhall ſo ſeek their own
Things, as not to concern themſelves for the Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt of Chriſt, but
retain, or through Covetouſneſs, keep back that which his Church,
VVorſhip, and publick Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts calls for, and by which means, his
bleſſed Intereſt ſhould ſink and languiſh in their Hands, who were
intruſted with it; certainly, they will be, and are looked upon, as great
robbers of God now, as thoſe were then, of whom the Prophet ſpeaks.</p>
            <p>Would to God this were conſidered; which of the Nations (as if
God ſhould ſay) have robbed their Gods: But bluſh ye <hi>Jews,</hi> for
ye have robbed me, and therefore ye are curſed with a curſe; your Sin, your
Sacriledg, of which you are guilty hath ſo provoked me, and the curſe
ſhall abide upon you, ſo long as ye abide, and continue in this ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful
Courſe; ſtrange that you dare Sin, whilſt I am puniſhing you for this
Ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity (ſo the <hi>Annotators</hi>) will you go<pb n="65" facs="tcp:30333:40"/>on in
your Sin, whilſt you are under the Judgment and Curſe of your God?
<hi>Bring ye all the Tithes into my Store-houſe, that there may be Meat in
mine Houſe, and prove me now herewith, ſaith the Lord of Hoſts; If I will
not open the Windows of Heaven, and pour you out a Bleſſing that there be
not room enough to receive it,</hi> verſ. 10. (Though we do not ſay) God
hath brought the like curſe now; yet we fear the Lords People in
<hi>England,</hi> both in City and Country, are under juſt Rebuke in
retaining that from God, for the Uſe of his Publick Worſhip, Service and
Miniſtry, which he Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires and Commands them to bring in, and lay up in his
Spiritual Houſe; and hence it is he is provoked, and ſeems to bring a
blaſt inſtead of a bleſſing up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on us; we fear we have Cauſe to ſay,
and cry out with our Apoſtle, <hi>All ſeek their own, and none the things
that are Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus Chriſts, Phil.</hi> 2.21. Do you think the Service of Gods
Houſe can be carryed on without any Charge, or is God leſs careful of his
Church and Miniſtry un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der<pb n="66" facs="tcp:30333:41"/>the Goſpel, than he was under
the Law. The firſt Church that was plant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed after the Aſcention of
Chriſt, were ſo Zealous and Piouſly inclined to the Service of the
Goſpel, that they ſeem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to give up all they had for the pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick
Intereſt of Chriſt, and ſold their Poſſeſſions, which thing you
are not required to do; you may keep your own Propriety in your Goods, Lands
and Poſſeſſions; but yet, nevertheleſs ought you to conſider your
ways, and not let the Intereſt of Chriſt, and the Goſpel to ſink under
your Hands: <hi>Will you dwell in your Ceiled Houſes, and let this
Houſe,</hi> i.e. <hi>The Lord's Houſe lye waſt?</hi> Eſpecially,
conſidering 'tis the Lord's Time, we are verily perſwaded in which he is a
going about to build it, and add to the glory of it; What proof have you given,
O ye Chriſtians and Members of the Churches! that you love Jeſus Chriſt
more than Father or Mother, yea, more than Son and Daughter? Which if you do
not, our Saviour ſaith ye are not worthy of him;<pb n="67" facs="tcp:30333:41"/>and what
Demonſtration can we ſee of this thing, whilſt you thus purſue the
World, and indeavour to lay up, nay, and daily do part with ſo many Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred
of Pounds, to ſuch a Son, and to ſuch a Daughter; and yet can't ſpare the
Twentieth Part thereof for Chriſt his Church and Publick Miniſtry? Our
Souls mourn and grieve to ſee what an Earthly and Covetous Spirit is got into
the Profeſſors of this Age, and fear that that Zeal is much gone; for the
Truth and fervent Love to Chriſt, which was once amongſt thoſe who were
his Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple; does it not appear ſo? Whilſt ſome of the Churches ſeem to
be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tented with any, nay, the meaneſt Gifts that are amongſt them,
provided they can have them without any Charge, rather than they will ſeek
out, and indeavour for an Able and Hono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Miniſtry, becauſe of that
great ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence and coſt they fear then they ſhall be at: As alſo,
whilſt Careleſs and mind not what want of Faithful Labou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers there may be
abroad in other Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces<pb n="68" facs="tcp:30333:42"/>and Churches, ſo that they are
provided themſelves: As likewiſe, do not give proper and meet Incouragment
for the raiſing up, and continuing of an Able Miniſtry for the time to
come. Theſe things are Lamentable, and great ground of Mourning and bitter
Tears: Know ye therefore this, and believe it, that God is offended, and may
juſtly blaſt you in your Trades, and Worldly Subſtance, if he hath not
al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready, becauſe you do not lay this Evil to Heart; and that which you think
ye ſave this way, may bring a blaſt upon all you have; and while you look
for much, ye may carry in little, and that which you do gain and bring home,
may be put into a Bag with Holes, <hi>Hag.</hi> 1 6. pray Read the 6. <hi>v. Ye
looked for much, and lo it came to little, and when ye brought it home, I did
blow upon it. Why, ſaith the Lord of Hoſts? Becauſe of mine Houſe that
is waſte, and ye run every Man to his own Houſe.</hi> Many Perſons we
have amongſt us, meet daily with great Diſappointments, Loſſes, and 
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:30333:42"/>manifold Afflictions, diverſe manner of ways, and wonder
at it, and are troubled at the Thoughts; but we fear do not lay to Heart, nor
conſider from whence it is, nor the chief Cauſe there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of; which
poſſibly may be, becauſe you have not diſcharged your Duty to Chriſt,
for the promoting of his bleſſed Goſpel, and Intereſt in the World; but
have ſhewed much more Love to, and Care of your own Houſes, and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns
than for the Houſe and Church of God: God may ſay of you, O ye
Profeſſors! you have toiled and been at great Coſt and Labour; and have
expected, hoped, and promiſed your ſelves great Increaſe; but you have
clearly diſcerned, and were ſenſible that it anſwered not your
Expectation, much of it dwindled into very little; you were looſers, and went
backward ſtill, which you have not regarded nor laid to Heart; but have let
my Houſe lie as it were waſte; nothing was too much in your Eyes to lay out
on your own Houſes and Buildings, to Adorn<pb n="70" facs="tcp:30333:43"/>and Beautifie
them; nor did you grudge to provide Sumptuous Proviſion and Apparel for your
Selves, and for your Sons, and Daughters: Nay, have idle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and in
ſuperfluities expended much Treaſure to gratifie your Luſt, and yet have
let my poor Children and Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Miniſters want ſuch things that were
Neceſſary for them, and not been con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned to encourage an able and
pain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Miniſtry, that the periſhing Souls of Sinners up and down in the
Nation might have the Bread of Life; and from hence is it that your Trades
fail, and your Labours bring in but little increaſe<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> But if once you
reform your doings, and ſhew your Zeal for the Goſpel, and Love to me, and
act as becomes a People profeſſing my Name; you ſhall ſee you ſhall
not be loſers by it; for <hi>I will open the Windows of Heaven, and pour you
out a bleſſing, that there ſhall not be room enough to receive it:</hi>
Nay, ſaith he, <hi>Prove me now if I do not do it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>We conclude, the Judgment on the one hand for ſuch a great Evil
and neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect<pb n="71" facs="tcp:30333:43"/>of Duty herein, and Mercies and Bleſſings
promiſed on the other hand, may be a great Argument to provoke you to a
Faithful Diſcharge of thoſe Obligations that lye upon you in this matter.
If you have a Deſire to be bleſt in your Bodies, Souls, and Eſtates, take
Care of God's Houſe, and bring in your Stores, that there may be Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion
for his Poor, and for his Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters. But if you neglect this Duty, and
perſue the World, and prefer your own Houſes and Things above thoſe great
Things of God and his Goſpel, you may look for a blaſt.</p>
            <p>Twelfthly, <hi>Conſider the Zeal of the Heathen of Old, and that
of the Antichri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian Party of latter Times;</hi> the former ſpared no
Coſt nor Pains to Beautify and Garniſh their Idols, <hi>they laviſh Gold
out of the Bag,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Iſa.</hi> 46. They took it by handfuls as it
were, and never told it, as ſome conceive, not matter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing what Coſt or
Charge they were at; ſith it was for the Adorning of their Gods: <hi>The
Goldſmith ſpreadeth it over<pb n="72" facs="tcp:30333:44"/>with Gold, and caſteth
Silver Chains.</hi> Iſa. 40.10. <hi>He is</hi> (ſaith the Prophet) <hi>ſo
impoveriſh'd that he hath no Oblation,</hi> that he can hardly procure Money
ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent to buy the meaneſt Sacrifice for his Gods; he is ſo Zealous
for his Idols, that he will one way or another find Money to procure the
choiceſt Mate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rials, ſaith the Annotators, and get the help of the beſt
Artiſt to make it, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Did they ſhew ſuch Zeal for, and Love
to them who were no Gods: And ſhall not ſuch be aſhamed and bluſh, who
have been ſo niggerly and ſparing to help on the Service and Worſhip of
the True and Living God? They would have the <hi>beſt Artiſt,</hi> and
moſt <hi>Curious Workman</hi> to do their Buſineſs, though they
impoveriſhed themſelves; but ſome of you, we fear, can be contented with
<hi>very unskilful Men,</hi> to carry on the Work of the God of Heaven, ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
than be at the Charge to diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bute of your Treaſure for the better
Improvement of them which you im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy, or to procure ſuch who you have 
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:30333:44"/>not amongſt your ſelves; and as for the
<hi>Papiſts,</hi> you cannot be Ignorant what vaſt Treaſure they have
from time to time freely beſtowed on their Church, and large Revenues
appointed for their Prieſts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and have they not commonly when
they come to dye; beſides all this, left large Legacies for Spiritual Uſes,
as they call them, and all to carry on their filthy Idolatry. But how little
haſt thou, O Profeſſor parted with to this day, for the uphold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the
Church of God, and carrying on the Miniſtration of the Goſpel of Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus
Chriſt? Thou haſt not ſhewed that Zeal for the True God, which ſome
have ſhewed for a Falſe One: Nor that Care of, and Love to the True
Worſhip of God, which others have ſhewed for Idolatry: May not theſe
Carnal and Antichriſtian Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thens one Day riſe up in Judgment a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt
you?</p>
            <p>Obj. <hi>But may be you will Object and ſay, 'tis no marvel the
Papiſts give ſo<pb n="74" facs="tcp:30333:45"/>plentifully becauſe they think to
merit Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven thereby.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> What then? Will not you do as much for the Honour
of God, and to promote his Intereſt in the VVorld, as thou wilt do for the
Salvation of thine own Soul? If thou haſt Eternal Life meerly of Grace, or
through the Favour and Mercy of God, and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits of Jeſus Chriſt? How much
the more ſhould this lay thee under an Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligation to be Bountiful and
Liberal, to further and carry on, and promote the Goſpel, and the Glory of
God in the VVorld? or have you a mind to betray your own Sincerity? Doth not
Grace teach you better Doctrine, even to prefer the Honour of God, above
whatſoever is dear to you on Earth.</p>
            <p>Thirteenthly, This will render your Miniſters inexcuſable, if
they do not faithfully diſcharge their Duties in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Reſpect, to God and
his People; we mean, when you diſcharge your Duties to them, according to the
Law<pb n="75" facs="tcp:30333:45"/>of Chriſt, and Rule of Juſtice and
Righteouſneſs: What will they have to ſay, to excuſe their
Remiſsneſs and Omiſſions in a painful ſtudying Medi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation, and
preaching the VVord, and in viſiting the Flock, when you have freed them from
all manner of worldly Snares and Incumbrances, and comfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tably provided for
them all good Things? But on the contrary, if they come forth unprepared, and
feed you with Food that hath little Soul Nouriſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in it: How can you
blame them? or if they never go about all the Year to know the State of the
Flock as their Duty is, have they not a ready Anſwer and Excuſe? <hi>i.
e.</hi> VVhat ſhall become of our poor Families? VVhat can you ſay to them?
Can you excuſe them from indiſpenſible Duties? And ſay we will be
contented with what Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice you are able to do, and all to ſave your
Purſes: the Lord open your Underſtandings, and ſhew you the great Evil
there is in this neglect, in not complying with the VVill of God, 
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:30333:46"/>in communicating all good Things to them, who Preach the
Goſpel to you. And is it not from hence there is ſuch a complaint in ſome
parts of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, for want of the <hi>ſaving Food of God's Word?</hi> We
hear daily what a vaſt bleſſing thoſe Elders and Miniſters are of to
the People whereabouts they live, who are provided for by the Churches, over
what others be who are not taken off of their ſecular Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs, being not
maintained by the People; one Miniſter may do more than ſeveral ſuch do
or can do. Beſides, when once you come to acquit your ſelves, as good
Chriſtians ought in this Caſe; with what Comfort may you be able to give up
your Account to Chriſt? And with Joy and much Soul Peace lye down, not only
in your Beds; but alſo in your Graves, when you come to Dye.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="section">
            <pb n="77" facs="tcp:30333:46"/>
            <head>Motives to preſs the Duty of the Miniſters Main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance,
with an Anſwer to other Objections.</head>
            <p n="1">1. COnſider well, and remember that your Paſtors are the
Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters; nay, the Ambaſſadours of Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus Chriſt; ſuch who
repreſent his Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cred Majeſty, and have his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, for what they
act and do in his Name, and diſpenee the Myſteries of God to you, according
to their Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; therefore the Lord Jeſus will ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count that done to
Himſelf, which is done to his Miniſters: <hi>He that receiveth you</hi>
(ſaith he) <hi>receiveth me, and he that deſpiſeth you, deſpiſeth me,
Mat.</hi> 10.40. <hi>Luke</hi> 10.16. If the Name and Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of Chriſt
will beget an aw in you,<pb n="78" facs="tcp:30333:47"/>or his Matchleſs and
Unſpeakable Love Influence your Souls; there is no doubt but his word will
abide upon you, and cauſe you to diſcharge the Duty we have preſſed
upon your Spirits. If you acknowledge a Religious Reſpect and Reverence due
to the Son of God, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſe it in a humble Obedience to his word; and if you
Love him and value his Goſpel, treat not his Miniſters in an unworthy
manner: Have you not called them off from other Buſineſs? And are they not
your Servants? And is not from thence a Goſpel Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance due to them from
you, as is the wages of your other Servants? Tho we fear ſome give more to
the meaneſt Servants in their Houſe, than they to give to the Miniſters
of Chriſt.</p>
            <p n="2">2. 'Tis evident, they have a great Charge committed to their
Truſt, <hi>they watch for your Souls, as they who muſt give an account,
Heb.</hi> 13.17. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you ought to conſider them, and pity them,
and endeavour to aſſiſt them, and put them into the beſt Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity 
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:30333:47"/>you are able to do, that they may make full proof of their
Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, and <hi>be free from the Blood of all Men;</hi> 'tis the
Buſineſs of your own Salvation, and concern of your pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious and immortal
Souls, that your Miniſters are imployed in; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore 'tis much more
your own Intereſt than his, and from hence ought to make Conſcience of your
Duty; for if they can't <hi>give their account with Joy, that will not be
profitable for you:</hi> And how can they give an acccount of Joy con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning
you, when you have neglect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed one great and indiſpenſible Duty, by which
means they were rendred una<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to perform their VVork, as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came them? Nor
can indeed the Miniſtry ever be effectual to your Souls, if you be not
ſincere in Obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence under it: Beſides, as one obſerves, will you be
leſs Careful for your Souls, and their Eternal wellfare, than for your
Bodies, and the Comforts of a Temporal Life? Can you be content to lay out your
Strength and Subſtance<pb n="80" facs="tcp:30333:48"/>to provide for theſe, and neglect
the other? Is it not ſad, ſaith one to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider, <hi>How many there are
among Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſors, that live in this World, as if there were no Truth in
the report of that which is to come, and have the meaneſt eſteem of the
moſt neceſſary means of Salvation?</hi> viz. <hi>The Word and Ordinances
of Chriſt, and a Goſpel Miniſtry; ſome can expend perhaps an hundred
Pounds</hi> per Annum, <hi>more or leſs, for Ornaments or Delights to Adorn a
frail Carcaſe, but will grudg half ſo much for the poor Saints, or to the
ſupport of the Worſhip of the Goſpel, and his ſinking
Intereſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. Conſider how many Temptations and Soul diſcouraging
VVeakneſſes your Miniſters lye under continually, both from within and
without, if ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible of the greatneſs of their VVork; and of their own
inſufficiency: You know not their Fears, their Cares, their Tears, and how
hard they are put to it to keep up in their VVork, finding ſuch ſtrong
Oppoſitions made againſt them by the Enemy, continually, ſo 
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:30333:48"/>that you had need to Strengthen, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort, and Incourage
them, as much as you can; and not to add to their Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row, and make them
ſerve you in wants and neceſſities.</p>
            <p n="4">4. We might tell you alſo what the Apoſtle ſays in
reſpect of his Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty as a Miniſter, in forbearing to Work at all: Will
any of you ſay your Miniſters muſt labour and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide for themſelves,
when God hath Ordained the contrary; and alſo when the Apoſtle ſaith, he
had pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to forbear Working? See 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 9.6. <hi>Or I only and</hi>
Barnabas, <hi>Have we not power to forbear Working? We cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly</hi> (as well
as the reſt of Chriſt's Miniſters) <hi>if we will run out to the
ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt end of the Line of our Liberty in things, without having regard to
your Circumſtances, might forbear Working with our Hands, and expect that
thoſe a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong whom we Labour ſhould maintain it.</hi> So the
<hi>Annotators</hi> render it. Now, you would think this a hard thing, ſhould
any of your Paſtors make uſe<pb n="82" facs="tcp:30333:49"/>of their Liberty; yet if
they ſhould do it, provided they were Faithful in their Work and Office,
knowing alſo your Ability, we would know whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther any of you could charge
them with Sin, as we know you may and ought other Perſons, who work not and
though the Apoſtle did ſometimes Work, it was of choice, and to prevent the
glorying of thoſe falſe Apoſtles, and for ſome other Reaſons, which
upon ſpecial Circumſtances for that time he mentioneth, and yet he
ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts it amongſt his Afflictions.</p>
            <p>Queſt. <hi>Ought a Paſtor or Miniſter to make Terms with the
Church about his Maintenance, before he take the Charge of them?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We aſſert for no ſuch thing, he is to take
the Charge freely, and of a ready Mind: But we ſay there is as
indiſpenſable a Duty lies upon the People to provide Carnal or Tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral
good Things for him, as there lies upon him to provide Spiritual good 
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:30333:49"/>Things for them, and to give him Grounds to Believe they
will be Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful to Chriſt and to him, in their duty upon that account.</p>
            <p>Queſt. <hi>But what ſhall that Church do, who are not able to
allow a ſufficient Maintenance to their Paſtor?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We have a Three-fold An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer to this
Queſtion.</p>
            <p n="1">
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> If through the Poverty of the Church they
cannot provide for their Miniſter, they may make their Caſe and
Circumſtance known to other Siſter Churches, and deſire their Aid and
Aſſiſtance herein; but if they can have none, and the Church do their
Duty to the utmoſt themſelves, and yet they are not able to ſupply his
Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſities, then he muſt be contented to ſuffer with the Church.
But</p>
            <p n="2">2. If God Bleſs a Congregation with a plentiful Portion of
this Worlds Good, it is their Duty to make their Miniſters a Party with them
in their<pb n="84" facs="tcp:30333:50"/>Flouriſhing Condition (and as a late Author
ſaith) <hi>Conſidering the Place and Imployment he is in, and the Service
he attends, it would be extreamly unworthy to think they have done enough, if
his preſſing Neceſſities be anſwered; whilſt they themſelves
abound in Superfluities.</hi> But if the Congregation be poor, and there is no
helps to he had, then their Miniſter muſt and ought to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent to be
poor with them; yea, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyce to approve himſelf a Miniſter of Chriſt,
(as <hi>Paul</hi> did) by Hunger and Nakedneſs, if the Providence of God call
him thereto; but whilſt it is in the power of their Hands to provide bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
for him, God expects it from them; and let none deceive them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, <hi>GOD
is not mocked,</hi> nor will he ſuffer his Commands to be ſlighted and
evaded, without rendring a juſt re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buke to the Offender, <hi>For whatſoever
a Man Soweth that ſhall he Reap.</hi> Yet neceſſity is laid upon
Chriſt's Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, and woe be to them if they Preach not the
Goſpel.</p>
            <p n="3">
               <pb n="85" facs="tcp:30333:50"/>3. It may deſerve our moſt mature
Conſideration, whether a People may ſafely conſtitute themſelves into a
Church State, when not able to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide for a Miniſtry, eſpecially as the
Caſe may be circumſtanced; for poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibly they might very well joyn
them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves to another Congregation near unto them, and be a great help to
ſuch a Church, being Imbodied with them. And this we do ſay, For a People
to put themſelves into a Church State, is one of the moſt weightieſt
Things in the World, and ought with as great Care and Conſideration to be
done; we concluding in ſome places where there are many Churches near to each
other, it would be far better for ſome of thoſe ſmall and inſufficient
Socie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to unite themſelves to ſome other Congregation; and by that
means the weight of thoſe Indiſpencible Duties and Obligations that are
incumbent on them, would with much more eaſe be borne and anſwered, to the
Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour of Chriſt, Reputation of the Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel,<pb n="86" facs="tcp:30333:51"/>and their
own Edification: Moreover, if all Chriſtians ought to conſider whether they
may or ought to put themſelves into a Church State, except they have
Perſons fitly qualifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and furniſhed with Gifts and Graces for the
Miniſtry; which if they may not ſafely do, then by the ſame parity of
reaſon ought they to conſider whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther they may proceed therein, if they
know their own Inſufficiency in reſpect of their making a Goſpel
Proviſion for their Maintenance, unleſs they live remote from any other
Church, and ſo neceſſity put them upon their ſo doing.</p>
            <p>Obj. <hi>But is not this to build, that which you your ſelves
have deſtroyed,</hi> viz. <hi>Have you not diſclaimed against ſuch who
Preach for Hire?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We never went about we hope to deſtroy any
Inſtitution or Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance of Jeſus Chriſt, as the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters
Maintenance is, as has ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently<pb n="87" facs="tcp:30333:51"/>been proved. But for
Men to Preach for Hire, to make that their End, we mean in Preaching the
Goſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pel, we ſtill utterly diſclaim any ſuch Practice, and ſay 'tis a
low, carnal, and haſe End and Deſign, and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worthy of any Chriſtian
Man.</p>
            <p n="2">2. We have always diſowned, or do diſclaim againſt
<hi>Tythes</hi> or the <hi>Tenths</hi> of Mens Increaſe, declaring that
<hi>they</hi> are not the right of any Goſpel Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters by the <hi>Law of
Jeſus Chriſt,</hi> or the due of the Miniſters of the <hi>New
Teſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> by the appointment of the Lord Jeſus; being only a
<hi>Moſaical Rite,</hi> and that Law to be Abrogated, as <hi>Aa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rons</hi>
Prieſthood is.</p>
            <p n="3">3. We have always diſowned and declared againſt ſuch
Miniſters, who uſe to ſtrive to compell Men by out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward force to Pay them
what they call their dues, it looking ſo much like an Antichriſtian Spirit
and Practice, and not agreeable to the Goſpel of Jeſus Chriſt; were Love
to Chriſt, and the ſence of Duty, we find ought to be<pb n="88" facs="tcp:30333:52"/>the only prevailing Argument to excite and provoke every Man to his
Duty in this great Caſe. Moreover you muſt take heed you are not prejudiced
a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt your Dutys from miſtaken and falſe Concluſions; becauſe
ſome will not Preach unleſs you put into their Mouths, and ſo make a meer
Trade of Preaching. VVill you not anſwer the requirement of God to thoſe
who are the Faithful Miniſters of his Word? Becauſe ſome will not relieve
their Poor, unleſs they are forced to do it, Will you diſown your Duty to
the poor Saints, and not relieve them, but Object and ſay, 'tis too much like
the National practice? Or, do you not like <hi>Preaching</hi> after that
manner, <hi>i. e.</hi> with a Text, Doctrine, Reaſons, and Application;
becauſe ſuch, and ſuch do ſo, whom you diſown, and cannot have
Communion with. Let all ſuch weak <hi>Objections</hi> be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voided, and
mentioned no more for ever.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="89" facs="tcp:30333:52"/>Object. <hi>You have we fear ever done it; for
though we do belive 'tis the duty of the Churches to allow to their Paſtors a
comfortable Maintenance, who are low in the World, and ſo expoſed to the
diſtracting Cares of this Life, and thereby hindred in the diſcharge of
their Duty in the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry. Yet for rich Men who need it not, to have an
allowance, we ſee no reaſon for that.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We Anſwer, It is not an act of Charity (to
Miniſters that are poor) we plead for, But we have proved it is an Ordinance
of God, he hath been pleaſed <hi>to Ordain, that thoſe who Preach the
Goſpel ſhould live of the Goſpel:</hi> 'Tis their due as they are
<hi>Chriſts</hi> Miniſters; He is their Portion now, as well as formerly
under the Law, and have therefore as much right to it, as you have to your
Inheritance; and from hence he willed them when he firſt ſent them out,
<hi>to take no Money in their Purſes,</hi> &amp;c. And therefore the 
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:30333:53"/>State of ſuch you ſpeak of, can't ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>empt you from that
Ordinance, nor your duty to them; beſides, is it fit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting (think you) that
ſuch Miniſter who have Eſtates ſhould waſte their Subſtance, and
injure their Children in their Faithfulneſs to Chriſt in Preaching the
Goſpel, and in the ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices of your Souls: For their Work is ſuch, that
it calls for all their time and uttermoſt dilligence (in a right diſcharge
of their Duty therein) and therefore thereby they are prevented of Improving
what they have, for the future comfort and advantage of their Families: Nay,
and we have heard to our great trouble, how ſome wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Men, who have
Laboured fully to improve their Miniſtry (through the Peoples neglect of
their duty to them) have in proceſs of time ſunk in their Eſtates, and in
Truth have been brought to a low Condition; for 'tis rare to ſee a Paſtor
of our Churches to abound in Riches: Tho ſome (Bleſſed be God) may be
indifferent well to<pb n="91" facs="tcp:30333:53"/>paſs in the World: now to expoſe a
rich man to Poverty, or to let a poor man ſhift for himſelf under wants and
neceſſities, are Evils much of the like nature: and for a prevention of
both, God hath ordered it ſo, that neither of theſe things ſhould, or
ought to be. Therefore this neglect (in ſhort) ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſeth Miniſters to
Temptations (con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering the moral Duty that lies upon them, in common with
other men to provide for their Families) namely, to content themſelves in
doing but one part of their Work, <hi>viz.</hi> to Preach a Sermon or two in
the Week, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Now our deſires are that they may all be wholly
ſequeſtred to the Lord's Work and Service; and not be other ways im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploying
themſelves, when they ſhould be Preaching the Kingdom of God, but to Labour
to fulfill their Miniſtry they have received of the Lord, ſo that they may
have their Accounts to give up with Joy in the Day of Chriſt.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:30333:54"/>Object. <hi>But our Church is ſmall, and our
Paſtor can't take up all his time in the Lord's Work.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer.</hi> We Anſwer, If he wants work, who will hinder
him from fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing of his ſecular Buſineſs, provid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed he doth faithfully
and fully diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge every part of the duty of his Place and
<hi>Function?</hi> But do not the Neighbouring Villages, and places adjacent
want the Goſpel, having no Bread for their Souls, and this too by reaſon
ſuch Paſtors are unconcerned in this matter? and by which means 'tis
doubtleſs that the Glorious Goſpel is no more promulgated up and down in
dark and blind corners of this Nation, nor the Church increaſes no more;
Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides do not many poor Sinners daily pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh hereby for want of
Knowledg? Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren, 'tis not for our ſelves, but for the Lord, and his
ſinking Intereſt that we plead for; it grieves our Souls to hear what cries
there are in many parts<pb n="93" facs="tcp:30333:54"/>of this Kindom for want of Bread,
ſome being forc'd, we hear, to go twelve or ſixteen Miles to hear a Sermon;
now if Miniſters of Churches made it their whole Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs to Preach the
Word, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern themſelves for the promoting of the Truth, it would not be
as it is at this very time; nor can we think it ſhould be otherwiſe,
unleſs we had a travelling Miniſtry (which we fear we ſhall hardly find)
unleſs Paſtors and Teachers in the reſpective Chur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches were taken off of
all In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumbrances, and ſo give themſelves up to the Miniſtry of the
VVord.</p>
            <p>God has done great things for us, and hath opened a mighty door,
and ſhall not we do ſome great thing for Him? The Caſe, Bleſſed be
the Lord, is much altered: You may come now into any Town and none dare forbid
you, (if any one will but entertain you) and Preach the Goſpel; And ſhall
we not take care to anſwer this Mercy; and do what we can that the poor Blind
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:30333:55"/>VVorld may be Inlightened, and brought to the ſaving
Knowledge of Jeſus Chriſt? If the preſent <hi>Providence</hi> of God be
not anſwered by a due Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>provement to his Glory, and the fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therance of the
Goſpel: VVe may ſay with <hi>Solomon, Why is there a price in the Hand of a
Fool, ſeeing he hath no Heart to it,</hi> Prov. 17.16. By this time we hope
you may more clearly under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand us, and what we drive at, and earneſtly
deſire to ſee accompliſhed, <hi>viz.</hi> That Miniſters may not only
bear that Name, but with all Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fulneſs do the VVork, they are called to;
'tis not to preſs our People to Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter to ſuch Preachers who are Idle
and Negligent in their Buſineſs, whoſe Hearts and Hands are in the
VVorld, and eagerly purſue their own ſecular Affairs, and matter not what
becomes of the Intereſt of Jeſus Chriſt.</p>
            <p>No, 'tis to encourage the Faithful and Labourous Perſon, who is
wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling to give himſelf up to the Lord, in the Diſcharge of that great
Turſt<pb n="95" facs="tcp:30333:55"/>committed to him, and to Labour in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed in
Chriſt's Vineyard; it is in truth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhame for a Miniſter to receive the Lord's VVages, and not do
the Lord's VVork; ſome there are in the World
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hat do not deſerve the Name of
Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ers they doing the VVork of
the Lord ſo deceitfully.</p>
            <p>Our Churches alſo are 'tis like in ſome places in the Country
but ſmall, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>re like to be
ſmaller, if the Miniſtry <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
not awakened to become more La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourous: Are there not ſuch in ſome Towns,
who are hardly known by the Inhabitants to be Miniſters at
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ll, they are ſo little concerned
in Prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching, they are better known to be <hi>Farmers, Yeomen,</hi> and
<hi>Tradeſman,</hi> then Preachers of the Goſpel; they are in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>angled ſo in the Affairs of this Life,
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hat they have but little time to
mind <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he great Work they are called
to: We would ask ſome Miniſters, whether
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hey could not do much more, Preach
oftner, and in more Places, and take greater Pains, to promote the Goſpel,
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:30333:56"/>and gather in Souls to Chriſt, than they do? Certainly
they will and muſt ſay, yea, we might; VVhy what is the reaſon of your
not doing it? Ought we not with <hi>Mary</hi> to do what we can? VVe conclude,
this Omiſſion of Duty either ariſes from the evil of your own Hearts, or
elſe from the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſneſs and Neglect of the People, in Reſpect of their
Duty to you. (1.) It may ariſe from the Evil in your own Hearts, in that you
have not or do not eſpouſe the Intereſt of Jeſus Chriſt, equal with,
or above your own: Can any be contented in doing a little Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice for
Chriſt, tho his Intereſt ſinks in their Hands; whilſt they thrive in
their own concerns, and grow Rich in the VVorld: Lord, what will be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come of
ſuch Miniſters in the day o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
Judgment? Can they think to loo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
Chriſt in the Face with Comfort, tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> have been ſuch ſlothful Servants; bu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> God forbid there ſhould be any among us who mind more
thei<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> own trifling Affairs, than the
grea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="97" facs="tcp:30333:56"/>VVork and
Buſineſs of their bleſſed Lord and Maſter? Is this <hi>the making
full Proof of your Miniſtry you have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived of the Lord?</hi> Chriſt's
Miniſters are called <hi>Labourers,</hi> but we fear ſome Labour but
little, unleſs it be at their own work: ſhould you be as Remiſs in your
own Affairs, as poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly you are in the Lords, you would find quickly a
decay in your Eſtates, and be in a ſinking Condition in the World; which
'tis like, would ſoon ſtartle you, and ſtir you up to greater Care and
Induſtry; and ought you not to be as conſiderate in the great con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cernment
of Chriſt, his Goſpel and Churches? We take it not upon us to reprehend any
of you but in Love (as fellow Servants may do) to caution you; pray remember,
you have the moſt ſacred Intereſt and Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of Jeſus Chriſt
committed to your Truſt; 'tis the greateſt Charge in the World, and you and
we muſt be cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed to an Account,
if Souls periſh in their Sins, and <hi>the Watchman gives not
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:30333:57"/>ſuitable warning, the Blood of thoſe Sin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners God will
require at the Watchman's Hands,</hi> Zeck. 3. Miniſters ought to be the
Light of the World, they ſhould ſhine therefore in Life and Doctrine, to
all round about where they live, that the People may know they have a
<hi>Noah,</hi> a Preacher of Righteouſneſs amongſt them. But</p>
            <p n="2">2. This grand fault may ariſe from the Peoples
Remiſneſs of Duty to their Miniſters; for hark, do we not hear many
worthy and faithful Paſtors cry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out? Alas Brethren, we are no more in the
Lord's VVork, no more in Preaching, in Viſiting, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Becauſe
our Families would ſuffer want, and what is neceſſary for them; we
ſhould gladly make the Goſpel our whole Buſineſs, and not only watch
over, and feed our own Flocks, but Preach the Goſpel up and down in Towns and
Villages, lying near us, if we knew how our VVives and Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren might be
provided for; for ſhould we neglect that great Moral and indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpenſible 
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:30333:57"/>Duty, how would the Holy Name of God be reproached? Alas,
our Souls are bowed down in us, we muſt confeſs, we have daily calls to
Preach, in this and that place, where to this day there has hardly been any
Meeting; but we are not able to do it, and therefore, we are forc'd to ſend
to <hi>London,</hi> that ſome Miniſters might come down into our Parts, to
Anſwer that great Call and Cry of Men and VVomen, for want of the Bread of
Life.</p>
            <p>This is a hard Caſe indeed, <hi>i. e.</hi> for the Servants of
Chriſt to have the due ſenſe of the greatneſs of their work upon their
Hearts, but cannot diſcharge it according as they ſee there is a Call and
Occaſion, by Reaſon the People neglect their Duty to them: But how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, do
what you can, and venture out, God will provide for you, and move upon the
Hearts of ſuch you Preach the Goſpel to, or ſome other way provide for
you: Improve this preſent Liberty, and do not <hi>let<pb n="100" facs="tcp:30333:58"/>the
Lord's Houſe lie waſte:</hi> Remember, <hi>Neceſſity is laid upon you,
and wo be to you, if you Preach not the Goſpel,</hi> be not Unbelieving, but
truſt the Providence of God; great things he expecteth from us, who has ſo
gloriouſly and graciou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſly appeared for us, and for the Land of our
Nativity.</p>
            <p>Nevertheleſs, Let none miſtake us; we do not ſay, 'tis
unlawful for Preachers to VVork or follow Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; but as Preaching doth not
make VVorking unlawful, neither ſhould any VVorldly Buſineſs hinder
Preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, therefore when working with our Hands will further the Goſpel, we
may VVork; we have a Call ſo to do (which was once <hi>Paul</hi>'s Caſe)
but when working at Trades and Callings, does palpably tend to the hinderance
of the Promulgation of the Goſpel; we muſt give over ſuch VVorking, and
wholly give up our ſelves to Preaching <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 'Tis but to make an
Expediment, if the People ſhould fail you: You know your Liberty, he that
Laboured with<pb n="101" facs="tcp:30333:58"/>his Hands, hath by that Example ſet the
Conſciences of Miniſters at Liberty, to provide for the Neceſſities of
this Life, by other Imployments, when they cannot Live of the Goſpel; but
this very thing <hi>Paul</hi> accounted amongſt his Afflictions; and
certainly, it muſt needs be a ſore Grief and Exerciſe to any Godly
Preacher in this Reſpect, <hi>i. e.</hi> when he hears People calling him,
one Day to this Town to Preach, and ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Day to that, and he finds he
can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not Anſwer neither of their Calls, through the Neceſſities of his
Famly; and the truth is, all do readily grant, that no poſitive Duty can
Diſcharge a Man from the Obligations of that pure Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral and Univerſal Duty
of providing for his Families.</p>
            <p>Brethren, you know when the Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veſt proves catching, and the
Painful and Laborious Harveſt-men are taken off of their Buſineſs, then
they may do a little VVork for themſelves, but when 'tis good Harveſt
weather, and the Harveſt is great, and the Labourers<pb n="102" facs="tcp:30333:59"/>but
few, they muſt ſtick to it and La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour hard.</p>
            <p>Even ſo when the late <hi>Storms of Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution</hi> were
upon us, many of <hi>Chriſt's Spiritual Harveſt-men</hi> were much hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred
and taken off of their Work, and did may be imploy themſelves o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe,
in their other Affairs (few being willing to open their Doors to them;) but now
the Providence of God has opened a great Door for the Goſpel, and ſent us
Bleſſed Harveſt Weather, and the Labourers alas! be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing alſo very few,
though the Harveſt is very great: How ought we to ſtick to our
Buſineſs?</p>
            <p>There was never certainly ſuch a Call to Miniſters to Work for
God as there is now; therefore that Servant that will not do his
<hi>beſt</hi> at ſuch an Hour, is like <hi>the Son</hi> (that
<hi>Solomon</hi> ſpeaks of) <hi>that Sleeps in Harveſt and ſo cauſeth
Shame.</hi> And as a wiſe Husband-man will not neglect a fit opportunity of
gathering in his Corn, upon preſumption of<pb n="103" facs="tcp:30333:59"/>much fair
Weather to come: So ought not we to loſe the preſent Seaſon for gathering
in Souls to Chriſt, not know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing how ſoon Clouds may riſe, and another
Storm overtake us, when we cannot Work for God as now we may; and if you have
not ſuch Incourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment as you ought to have from the People, yet remember
when Night comes, the Lord Jeſus will well reward you for all the pains you
take in his Work; yet ſince our Saviour ſaith the Labourer is worthy of his
Hire, we can't think any (when they conſider the Matter a little better) will
any way obſtruct, or hinder you in your Buſineſs through their neglect of
Duty to you.</p>
            <p>Object. <hi>But doth not Chriſt tell his Diſciples? As they
had freely received, ſo they ſhould freely give.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> We Believe this Text is not taken, or
underſtood according to the meaning of our Saviour; for it cannot 
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:30333:60"/>mean that Chriſt's Miniſters ſhould receive neither
Money, Meat, or Clothes, whilſt they are imploy'd in his Work and Service,
becauſe in the very next Verſe he bids them <hi>Provide neither Gold nor
Silver, nor Braſs in their Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, nor two Coats, nor Scrip for their
Journey;</hi> becauſe he plainly intimates all ſuch things they were worthy
of, and might expect them from the People to whom they Preached. Therefore 'tis
an horrible abuſe put upon the Text, to take the Words in that Senſe; as if
our Bleſſed Maſter ſhould forbid his Servants to receive a Maintenance
from the People; for then indeed they might have ſaid, Lord, If we muſt
Preach ſo freely as not to receive any thing, it behoveth us to provide well
for our Journey; but ſince they were forbid to do ſo, it is clear that
could not be our Saviours meaning: Beſides, ſuch a Sence is directly
oppoſite or repugnant to thoſe other Precepts the Lord Jeſus hath laid
down by his A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſtles in the <hi>Epiſtles;</hi> wherein it is po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitively
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:30333:60"/>aſſerted (as you have heard) that <hi>He that is
taught in the Word ought to Communicate to him that Teacheth in all good
things,</hi> 1 Tim. 5.18. <hi>And that they who Miniſter at the Altar
ſhould par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take of the Altar; God having Ordained that he that Preaches the
Goſpel, ſhould live of the Goſpel,</hi> 1 Cor. 9.14. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore we rather
are of the Opinion (in reſpect to this Text) with a late wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy VVriter;
<hi>The Doctrine</hi> (ſays he) <hi>they were to Preach, they were Impowered
to Confirm with Miracles; which</hi> (ſay they) <hi>He gives them a Charge
they ſhould Work freely, without receiving any Reward for them; that the
Miracles might not be uſed to their private Profit, but to the End they were
appointed of God, which was the Confirmation of their Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. It may alſo teach us that Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters ought not to
make a Bargain with the People, or deſire to know what they ſhall have
before they en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter on their Work; for he who would approve himſelf a true
Miniſter of Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus<pb n="106" facs="tcp:30333:61"/>Chriſt, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> not to
Preach for Hire or filthy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>cres
ſake, <hi>i. e.</hi> that ought not to be the thing he aims at; that's a low
and baſe deſign, but as you know Churches provide and ought to provide for
the Poor; yet ſhould any ſeek to come into your Communion meerly for a
Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, you would ſay he or ſhe that did ſo, were no better than
Hypo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crites, and (may ſay truly) yet that would not free you from
communicating to poor Faithful Chriſtians. Even ſo, if ſome deceitful and
carnal Perſons ſhould undertake the Work of the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtry for filthy
Lucres ſake, and not in Love to Chriſt, and to promote his Intereſt and
Glory, they, doubtleſs act contrary to this Precept of Chriſt. But yet
nevertheleſs, the Church i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> bound
to communicate and allow a comfortable Maintenance to her Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful
Miniſters; and as he freely, and of a ready Mind, and for Chriſt's ſake,
Preaches the Goſpel, and is bound ſo to do if he will approve himſel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <pb n="107" facs="tcp:30333:61"/>Faithful; ſo in
like manner are the People and Churches of God bound freely and of a ready mind
to Miniſter to them, if they would ſhew to all they are Faithful
Chriſtians, ſuch who have an equal reſpect to all Chriſts Commands and
Deſire, to the utmoſt of their Abilities, to further and not hinder the
promulgation of the Goſpel in the World.</p>
            <p>But by the way it is plain, had it not been the practice of the
Goſpel Churches in the Apoſtles time, to allow their Paſtors a
Maintenance, what room was there for the Apoſtle to caution any Miniſter or
Elder not to undertake the Work for filthy Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cres ſake, but of a ready mind.
More<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>over, very remarkable is it to conſider how the <hi>Prieſts of God
under the Law</hi> were to receive <hi>that Portion Jehovah gave them:</hi>
They were not (as Mr. <hi>Ainſworth</hi> noteth) <hi>To receive it after a
baſe or ſervile manner, but as Gifts due to the Lord, and to them from him:
The</hi> Hebrew Canons (ſaith he) <hi>ſhew the Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raelites 
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:30333:62"/>were to give them their Portion with Honour; and it was
unlawful for the</hi> Prieſts <hi>or</hi> Levites <hi>to ſnatch away the
Heave-Offering, or the Tithes; yea,</hi> ſaith he, <hi>if they did but ask
their Portion with their Mouth it was unlawful.</hi> Read his Annotation on
<hi>Numb.</hi> 18. v. 12. And then on <hi>Deut.</hi> 18.3. He ſaith again,
<hi>the Prieſt might not violently take the Gifts, nor ask them with his
Mouth, but he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived them when they were given him with Honour.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This may teach us two things. Firſt, that Chriſt's Servants
ought to take heed they ſhew all true and real Zeal and Love to Chriſt,
when they un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertake his Work and Service; and not to ſhew ſuch a ſervile
and baſe Spirit as to demand their Portion that God has Ordained for them,
but leave it to the free will Offering of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple. Secondly, It may alſo
teach Churches to ſee they do neither with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold the Miniſters Portion from
them, nor give it them grudgingly, or in an unbecoming manner, but to hand out 
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:30333:62"/>to them what they need with due re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect and honour,
they being worthy of it, and are to receive it as their part and portion from
God, and as they are His Stewards and Faithful Labour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, by Virtue of a
Divine and Holy Law: Nay, and the Lord's People ought to be as careful in
diſcharge of this Duty to Chriſt's Miniſters now, as the
<hi>Iſraelites</hi> were to the <hi>Levites;</hi> tho' as we have already
ſaid, their Portion is not the <hi>Tithes of Mens Increaſe,</hi> nor
<hi>the Firſt Fruits,</hi> which Law is Abro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gated. Yet ſaith <hi>Reverend
Ainſworth,</hi> 
               <q rend="inline">'The Equity of that Law remaineth perpetually, as
the Apoſtle obſerveth, <hi>Do you not know that they which Miniſter about
Holy things, live of the things of the Temple; and they that wait at the</hi>
Altar, <hi>are partakers with the</hi> Altar: <hi>Even ſo hath the Lord
Ordained,</hi> &amp;c. 1. Cor. 13.14. Becauſe the Miniſters of God then
were injoyned to attend on His Service, he would not have them cumbred with
worldly Affairs,<pb n="110" facs="tcp:30333:63"/>leaſt (ſaith he) they ſhould be
hind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred from doing their Duties; as it is Written, <hi>No Man that Warreth
in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tangleth himſelf with the Affairs of this Life, that he may pleaſe him
who hath called him to be a Soldier.</hi> 2 Tim. 3.4. From hence God hath
ordered it thus for them.'</q> Moreover, <hi>the Hebrews ſay from hence
'twas</hi> Levi <hi>was not counted meeet to have Inheritance in the Land
of</hi> Iſrael, <hi>or Spoils with his Brethren, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe he was
ſeparated to Serve the Lord, and to Inherit him, and to teach his ſtrait
Ways, and his Just Judgments unto the People: therefore was he ſeparated from
the ways of the World; they wage not War, as the reſt of</hi> Iſrael
<hi>do, neither do they Inherit nor Earn for themſelves with the Strength of
their Bodies, but they are the Lords Power (or Substance) as it is
Written,</hi> Deut. 13.11. Bleſs Lord his Power; <hi>and the Bleſſed God
earneth for them, as it is Written</hi> Numb. 18.20. <hi>I am thy Part and
thine Inheritance.</hi> Maim. Treat. of the Releaſe and Jubilee, <hi>c.</hi>
13. <hi>f.</hi> 12.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="111" facs="tcp:30333:63"/>The reaſon of the ſame Law, 'tis evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent
of neceſſity does remain; the Work of Miniſters is great now, and 'tis as
Holy and as Honourable as ever, and the neglect of a Faithful diſcharge
herein, as great a Sin as it was then; and God's People have as great, nay,
greater Benefit and Divine Profit by the Miniſtry of the Goſpel, than
thoſe had who lived under the Law; be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides Chriſt's Servants have the
ſame need of it: moreover, our People are delivered from other great Burdens
and vaſt Charges that the People of <hi>Iſrael</hi> were continually at;
and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore how unjuſt and unreaſonable a thing is it to with-hold a fit
and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient Lively-hood from them. Nay, and we muſt ſay, that which any
with-hold from the Servants of God, is the Lord's, and none of theirs; for he
lays claim to part of their Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, as that which He has Ordain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to his
own ſpecial ſervice and uſe of His Faithful Miniſters.</p>
            <pb n="110" facs="tcp:30333:64"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#OXF" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="111" facs="tcp:30333:64"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" resp="#OXF" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <p>
               <pb n="112" facs="tcp:30333:65"/>Queſt. <hi>May every one then that
Preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>es expect an Allowance, though they Preach but now and then.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſw.</hi> That muſt be left to the Wiſdom and
Conſideration of the Church; who ought to conſider the Perſons
Circumſtances, with the Call he hath to Preach, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But
princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pally it belongs to thoſe who are ſet a part to that Work, whoſe
Strength and Time is taken up about the great Affairs of Chriſt and the
Goſpel.</p>
            <p>Thus we have indeavoured to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge our Duty as touching this
great Work, and have we hope Anſwered all the material Objections any have to
bring, or urge againſt the Miniſters Maintenance: But ſince we have a
little Room we ſhall add ſome brief hints further, to ſhew the great
charge and work of a true Goſpel Miniſter,<pb n="113" facs="tcp:30333:65"/>and ſo
conclude; that all may ſee how needful a thing it is, that every one take
care to diſcharge their Duty in this matter to them, whereby alſo the
Juſtneſs and Righteouſneſs of the Law, and appointment of God herein,
may yet further appear to all.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="section">
            <head>The Great and Weighty Work of a True Goſpel Miniſter
opened.</head>
            <p>THE Nature and Weightineſs of the Work of the Faithful Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant
of Chriſt, together with the ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity and difficulty of it, we ſhall
conſider in its parts in a brief and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendious manner.</p>
            <p n="1">
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> 'Tis a Holy and a ſublime Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice; he is
placed in a very high Sphere<pb n="114" facs="tcp:30333:66"/>and Station, hence called the
Ambaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſador of Chriſt; What higher Digni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty can be conferred on Man? The
greatneſs of the Prince whoſe Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſengers they are, ſets forth their
Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity; they are in Chriſt's ſtead Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed in the great Affairs of His
Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual Kingdom; and have received Authority from Him, and are alſo
prepared and qualified for this Sacred Work by Him, and indeed therefore ought
to be blameleſs, <hi>as the Stewards of God:</hi> And hence it is that
thoſe who are ſaid to receive them, receive Him; and thoſe who
deſpiſe them, deſpiſe Him. O! with what Holy Fear, Dread, and Reverence
ought they to enter upon this Work and Office, leaſt they ſhould
diſhonour their great and glorious Prince and Heavenly Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign, whom they
repreſent! Is it not a weighty thing to be made the Mouth of Chriſt?</p>
            <p n="2">2. Nay, and this is not all, they are intruſted with
matters of the higheſt moment in the World, Chriſt having 
<pb n="115" facs="tcp:30333:66"/>committed the Management of his Glorious Intereſts, and
great concerns he has on Earth into their Hands; they are ſent to treat with
poor Sinners about Eternal Matters, even the Eternal Life, or Eternal Death and
Damnation of their Precious and Immortal Souls, in and about theſe things
Miniſters of the Goſpel are Fellow Workers together with Chriſt. 2.
<hi>Cor.</hi> 6.1. Though but as Inſtruments, ſerving him as the prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipal
Agent, and efficient Cauſe: <hi>He trod the Wine-Preſs of his Fathers Wrath
alone;</hi> but in the Application of the purchaſe of Man's Salvation, he
admits of Fellow-workers, tho the internal Work be his, <hi>i. e.</hi> the
effects of his Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits upon the Souls of thoſe whoſe Hearts are changed;
yet there is a Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſterial part which lyeth on the faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Diſcharge of
the Miniſter's Duty, which conſiſteth partly in <hi>Exhortations,
Motives</hi> and <hi>Arguments,</hi> by the Ear con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyed to the Soul; and thus
Miniſters may be ſaid to be Workers together with Chriſt, and without him
they can do<pb n="116" facs="tcp:30333:67"/>nothing, they are Workers, but they muſt have
Chriſt Work with them, or they will find that they Labour in Vain.</p>
            <p>But is it not think you a high and moſt ſacred Place and
Office thus to be imployed? May not every one of us ſay, who are ſufficient
for theſe things, <hi>for we are unto God</hi> (ſaith the Apoſtle) <hi>a
ſweet ſavour of Chriſt in them that are ſaved, and in them that
periſh,</hi> 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 2. for that God whom we, ſerve, will not Judge
of us, nor reward us according to our Succeſs (as a wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Author
obſerves) but according to our Faithfulneſs and Diligence in his Work, we
give (as if <hi>Paul</hi> ſhould ſay) a good ſavour by our Doctrine unto
all, and our Labours are a ſweet ſavour in the Noſtrils of God, whatever
effects they have upon the Souls of Men; God accepteth of our Labours, as to
good Men, to whom we are Inſtruments of Eternal Life and Salvation; and
though others deſpiſe the Goſpel, and refuſe the ſweet ſound
thereof; yet as to them<pb n="117" facs="tcp:30333:67"/>alſo, we are a ſweet ſavour
in the No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrils of God, tho <hi>Iſrael</hi> be not ſaved, ſaith the
Prophet, yet I ſhall be glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous; it is not through any neglect in us, as to
our duty if any periſh, but from their own Willfulneſs and Rebel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lious
Hearts. <hi>To the one, we are the ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour of Death unto Death, and to the
other, the ſavour of Life unto Life. And who is ſufficient for theſe
things.</hi> ver. 16.</p>
            <p>As ſweet ſmells, which are to ſome pleaſant and
comfortable (ſaith a Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Author) yet are to others pernici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and
deadly; ſo it is with the ſweet ſavour of the Goſpel; the report which
we in all places make of Chriſt, to ſome (through their unbelief, and
hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of their Heart, and fondneſs of their Luſts) proveth; but the
Savour of <hi>Death unto Death,</hi> hardning their Hearts to their Eternal
Ruine and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction; but to ſuch who (being or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained to Eternal Life;
believe our Report, and) imbrace the Goſpel, and live up to the Precepts and
Rule there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of; our Preaching proves a Cauſe of<pb n="118" facs="tcp:30333:68"/>Spiritual
and Eternal Life to which that leadeth; but O how great a work is this! What
Man? What Angel, is ſufficient for it? O it is a mighty VVork to Preach the
Goſpel, as we ought to Preach it; it is that by which Faith cometh, <hi>How
ſhall they believe on him, of whom they have not heard? And how ſhall they
hear, without a Preacher? And how ſhall they Preach, except they are
ſent?</hi> Rom. 10.14. <hi>i. e.</hi> Unleſs they have an extraordinary or
ordinary Miſſion, <hi>i. e.</hi> either from God more immediately (which
Call is long ſince ceaſed) or elſe, by the Election of the Church, and
Ordination of the Elders, or Presbytery; this is neceſſary in all Regular
Miniſters: How elſe can they duly or profitably in the Name and Authority
of Chriſt, preach the Word of Life? Brethren, (you who are Chriſt's true
Miniſters being orderly called to this ſacred Work,) your Prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching hath
attendency, either to ſave, or eternally to condemn the Souls of Men; and
with what trembling then,<pb n="119" facs="tcp:30333:68"/>ought this Work to be undertaken
and performed; you are intruſted with Men's Souls, and muſt be accountable
for them; eſpecially, ſuch who are committed to your Charge; did we
conſider it, and duly ponder upon it in our Minds, certainly, we ſhould
have little elſe to think upon, nor trouble our Heads and Hearts about, it
would be ſure cauſe us to be more Serious, and Laborious, we are
perſwaded, than we are: VVhat ſhall we do, if through our Neglect and
Remiſneſs in this great VVork, any ſhould die and periſh in their Sins?
Mind what God ſaith in that of <hi>Ezek.</hi> 3.18. Unto his VVatchman,
<hi>When I ſay unto the wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked, thou ſhalt ſurely dye, and thou
giv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt him not warning, nor ſpeakeſt to warn the wicked from his way, to
ſave his Life, the ſame wicked man ſhall die in his Iniquity, but his
Blood I will require at thine Hand;</hi> tho ſome do prophanely ſcoff and
deride, yet muſt we ſpeak to them, and warn them, until it do appear they
are ſuch as <hi>will turn again<pb n="120" facs="tcp:30333:69"/>and rend us,</hi> Men
muſt be told their Sins, and their Dangers, that ſo we (as Inſtruments in
God's Hand) may preſerve their Souls, and recal them a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> once both from Sin and Death, the Man who is not warned,
will certain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly die in his Sins, his Ignorance will not be ſufficient to
prevent his Ruin and Damnation; but if Miniſters admoniſh him not, warn him
not, that will in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>volve them alſo under Guilt and Dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, God will puniſh
ſuch Miniſters and Watchmen, who poſſibly might have ſaved thoſe
periſhing Sinners, however they ought to have warned them, And</p>
            <p>Hence how Careful was St. <hi>Paul,</hi> ſee <hi>Acts</hi>
20.26. that ye might be pure from the Blood of all Men; he appeals to the
Church of <hi>Epheſus,</hi> in that matter they knowing his great Care,
Faithful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and unwearied Induſtry, upon every Reſpect; and ſhews
that no Soul had been loſt through his default, he having ſincerely, and in
all ſimplicity declared to them the way of Life, and perſwaded them to walk
therein, and<pb n="121" facs="tcp:30333:69"/>had not kept back any part of the Will and
Mind of Chriſt from them, but had ſhewed them the whole Counſel of God,
<hi>and ceaſed not</hi> for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hree
Years (which was all the whole <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ime
he was amongſt them) <hi>to warn <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>very one Night and Day with Tears.</hi> Acts 20.31. The precious
Worth of the Immortal Souls of Men lay upon the Spirit and Conſcience of this
Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Apoſtle: And in this he laid forth himſelf as an Example for
all true and faithful Miniſters, who are in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oyned elſewhere to follow his Steps.
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f one Soul be worth more than all
the World; How great is the charge of Chriſt's Miniſters, that have many
Souls committed to their Care and Truſt? But</p>
            <p n="2">2. This is not all, they are Intruſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with that Holy,
High, and Peculi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ar Intereſt which Jeſus Chriſt hath
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ere below, which is dearer to him
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>han Ten Thouſand Worlds; He is
gone into Heaven, and hath left H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>
great Concerns He hath here <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
Earth to them to mind and look afte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:30333:70"/>and take
the care of: For the good of which, and to carry it on, and for the perfecting
of it: He hath ſhed His moſt Precious Blood, and given His Holy Spirit to
them in the Gifts and Graces of it, and appointed them a Livelyhood, without
being incum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bred with worldly Buſineſs; and hath alſo promiſed them a
Crown of Glory at laſt, if they abide Faithful to the end, aſſuring them
that they, and all others who turn many to Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs, ſhall ſhine
as the Stars for ever more. <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.2,3.</p>
            <p n="3">3. They are not only <hi>Stewards of the Myſteries of
God,</hi> 1 Cor. 4.1. But alſo Intruſted with the charge and care of his
Churches, and Holy Doctrine of the Goſpel; Miniſters are the Stewards of
Chriſt's Houſe: Moreover, <hi>It is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired in Stewards, that a Man be
found Faithful,</hi> 1 Cor. 4.2. Eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſuch Servants who are
entruſted with their Maſters Goods, to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penced out to others: Now
the Faithfulneſs of ſuch Stewards lies in
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>heir giving to every one their 
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:30333:70"/>due Portion, according to their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters order, and not
detaining any thing from others which he hath ordered them to have; the ſame
in quality, not <hi>Water inſtead of Wine, nor Droſs inſtead of
Gold:</hi> not <hi>Mens Inventions and Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions, inſtead of his Holy
Sacraments and Sacred Inſtitutions.</hi> And the ſame for quantity; not now
and then a ſmall Portion, but as Chriſt hath provided plenty, ſo they
ſhould plentifully hand forth to all His Servants: And they al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo muſt be
Faithful to cheriſh and ſtrengthen the Weak, and heal with all Skill and
Tenderneſs the wounded and ſickly Ones of Chriſts Family, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very way
improve their Maſters Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and do what they can to gather in Souls to him:
For one chief End of Goſpel Miniſtry is for the gathering together of the
Saints; as well as for the Edifying the Body of Chriſt; therefore in every
place where there is a Door opened for them, they muſt work hard whilſt
there are any Sin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners to be called into the Vineyard, and muſt not leave
their Maſters<pb n="124" facs="tcp:30333:71"/>Buſineſs to follow their own;
eſpecial<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly when they know not but Chriſt hath much People in and about the
place where they live, who are to be brought into His Fold.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> The neceſſity and uſeful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of their
Work and Miniſtration is opened by divers other <hi>Metaphors: viz.</hi> they
are called <hi>Shepherds;</hi> What would ſoon become of the Sheep, if the
Shepherd ſhould be careleſs, they will quickly go aſtray,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Wolf would devour them. They are called alſo Guides, and
of Old <hi>Seers</hi> and <hi>Watchmen;</hi> being ſet to diſcover and give
warning of approaching danger.</p>
            <p>The Greatneſs and Labouriouſneſs of their Work, is ſet
forth by their being called <hi>Planters, Builders,</hi> and
<hi>Labourers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Dignity</hi> and <hi>Honourableneſs</hi> of their Work
and Office is ſet forth by their being called <hi>Fathers, Angels,
Ambaſſadors, Stars and Rulers:</hi> Now from the whole it muſt needs
appear to all, that the Miniſters Work is hard and difficult: We may well
ſay, <hi>Who is ſufficient for theſe things?</hi> 'Tis ſuch a 
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:30333:71"/>Work that it cauſed ſome of God's Servants of Old, to
undertake it with much Trembling; nay it made <hi>Moſes</hi> to cry out,
<hi>Send by whom thou wilt ſend.</hi> Exod. 4.13,</p>
            <p>'Tis ſo hard and difficult, that a man with all his acquired
Parts is not ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient for it; nay, a Saint with all his Spiritual Gifts
and Graces is not able to perform it without freſh ſupplies of renewed
Strength every Day.</p>
            <p>But to proceed, the difficulty of the Miniſters Work lies in
theſe reſpects following.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> In regard of themſelves who are Imployed in
it.</p>
            <p n="1">1. They are but Men; <hi>Son of Man I have made thee a
Watchman.</hi> And as they are men, ſo commonly they are not the wiſeſt
and moſt learned in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of humane Parts and Knowledg neither. <hi>You
ſee your Calling Brethren.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. Man at beſt is but a Worm, he is but a poor
dark-ſighted Creature, <hi>we</hi> (ſaith the Apoſtle) <hi>know but in
part.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. Man at beſt with all his Accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhments, is
attended with Weakneſs,<pb n="126" facs="tcp:30333:72"/>and carries about with him, <hi>a
Body of Sin and Death.</hi> Rom. 7.</p>
            <p n="4">4. Man at beſt with all his Heavenly Graces, hath but
ſmall Skill, and ſhort Experiences.</p>
            <p n="5">5. Man at beſt is ſubject to great Diſcouragements,
and lyable to many grievous Temptations.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Secondly,</hi> The difficulty of their Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs, lies in
the Work it ſelf, the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters Imployment is hard, and no ways eaſie.
Becauſe,</p>
            <p n="1">1. 'Tis a Myſterious VVork, what Myſteries are greater
than thoſe a Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter is to ſtudy, and dive into? <hi>Without
Controverſy, great is the Myſtery of God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lineſs.</hi> 1 Tim. 3.16.
<hi>But we ſpeak the Wiſdom of God in a Myſtery, even the hidden
Wiſdom.</hi> 1 Cor. 2.7.</p>
            <p>That which the moſt wiſe, and knowing in the ſame Art, can
reach or underſtand but part of, muſt needs be a great Myſtery; but ſo
it is here, for the Apoſtles who had the greateſt and cleareſt Knowledge
of theſe My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteries, as any ever had in the VVorld; yet declare, they
<hi>knew but in part, and<pb n="127" facs="tcp:30333:72"/>ſaw but in part, darkly, as
through a Glaſs. ver.</hi> 13.9.12. 'Tis ſuch a Myſtery, that <hi>he that
thinks he knows any thing, knows nothing, as he ought to know.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>VVhat a Myſtery is that of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>carnation of our Lord Jeſus?
That the Nature of Man ſhould be joined to the Divine Nature of God, and both
make but one Chriſt.</p>
            <p>What a Myſtery is there in the Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine of Faith? 1. That a Man
ſhould go out of himſelf, and be carried above himſelf, to believe things
impoſſible to Man's Natural Reaſon, that he ſhould ſeek for
Juſtification, by the Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and Obedience of another; for a Man
(as one would think) to have a great ſtore of Holyneſs, and good Works, and
yet throw it (as it were) all away, and be dead to it in point of Truſt, and
Dependance, is to Natural Men a ſtrange Myſtery. 2. To believe when every
thing is oppoſite to it: To Work for Life, and oppoſe ſome Sin, a Natural
Man is ready to do; but to believe in Chriſt, for Life and Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyneſs, to
rely on his Doings, his Works,<pb n="128" facs="tcp:30333:73"/>his Merits; this the Heart
of Man can't underſtand, but is naturally averſe to; nay, and Satan alſo
oppoſeth it, and the World mocks at it, and accounts it Fooliſhneſs. 3.
That a Man ſhould believe and not ſee; nay, believe as <hi>Abraham</hi>
did, in hope, againſt hope is a Myſtery.</p>
            <p>Yet, may be there are ſome greater Myſteries than this which a
Miniſter is to Study, in reſpect of Chriſt the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diator; his Work,
Offices, Glorious Covenant, Ordinances, and Providences of God in the World,
and therefore his VVork is a difficult VVork.</p>
            <p n="2">2. 'Tis difficult, in that it calls for the greateſt Care
and Exactneſs imagi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable, every thing muſt be done accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, to the Holy
Pattern ſet by Chriſt in the Goſpel, there muſt be no ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to, no
diminiſhing from, nor al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering of any thing in the leaſt, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out eternal
hazard and danger.</p>
            <p n="3">3. 'Tis difficult and very hard in that it calls for the
greateſt ſtrength that the moſt ſtrong in Grace and Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom can
arrive unto, it requires all the Powers of the whole Soul to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erted 
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:30333:73"/>or put forth to a right Diſcharge thereof.</p>
            <p n="4">4. It calls not only for all our ſtrength, but alſo all
our Time and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligence; a ſlothful or Idle Perſon is not fit to be a
Miniſter, 'tis a work that muſt be followed continually, let the times be
what they will; <hi>Preach the Word, be inſtant in ſeaſon, and out of
ſeaſon, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove, exhort, with all long Suffering, and Doctrine;</hi> be
not Slothful, but Diligent, fear no Faces, regard no Threats, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect no
Mans Perſon, reprove all im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>partially, be no fawning nor flatter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
Preacher; nor like thoſe who ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther vent their own Paſſion, than
per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue the end of Inſtruction, and Refor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of Souls; and this is a
hard Work to do.</p>
            <p n="5">5. 'Tis difficult Work, in reſpect of the oppoſition
that is made againſt them, and the Grand Obſtructions they meet withal.</p>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>From their own Hearts, the Fleſh is weak, tho the
Spirit indeed is willing,</hi> many times, that it is ready to ſay with
<hi>Peter, Maſter, pity thy ſelf;</hi> Why doſt<pb n="130" facs="tcp:30333:74"/>thou
ſpend thy Time, thy Strength, and ware out thy poor Body at this ſort?
Leſs may do, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Beſides, The Heart of a Miniſter (who is ſenſible of the
Nature of his Work,) cauſes him oft to tremble, in Conſideration of his
Unfitneſs, and Unworthineſs for ſuch a ſacred Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taking and
Imployment.</p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>From Sin,</hi> in dwelling Sin, and other Humane
Frailties; alas, they are Men of like Paſſion and Infirmities with
others.</p>
            <p n="3">3. <hi>From Satan,</hi> he is an Implacable Enemy to them,
and to their Work; hence he raiſes up all the Oppoſition againſt them
imaginable, to hinder them in their Buſineſs, or take them off of it, or
make them Remiſs and Neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligent in doing it, <hi>we are not Ignorant</hi>
(ſaith <hi>Paul</hi>) <hi>of his devices.</hi> 2 Cor. 2.11.</p>
            <p n="4">4. <hi>From the World,</hi> 1. by Reproaches and
Contradictions of Ungodly Men, 2. By Hereticks and Falſe-Teachers, with
theſe they are forc'd to fight, and many times are hard put to it, as
<hi>Paul</hi> when he ingaged thoſe evil Beaſts at <hi>Epheſus.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="5">
               <pb n="131" facs="tcp:30333:74"/>5. Laſtly, <hi>By Perſecutors,</hi>
allways the heat of this Battle falls upon Chriſt's poor Miniſters; they
are the Mark theſe wicked Archers ſhoot at; hence they like <hi>Paul</hi>
are oft in Bonds, and Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoners for Chriſt's ſake.</p>
            <p>Now, put all theſe things together, and is it not needful (think
you) that your poor Miniſters be thought upon, and incouraged by you, as
Chriſt hath appointed? But we ſhall ſay no more, only, conclude all with
one VVord to our <hi>Fellow Labourers.</hi> Brethren, let us ſtrive to double
our Diligence, and ſhew to all the ſenſe of the greatneſs of our work
is upon our Spirits; and tho we have not that incouragement from the People
that God has Ordained; yet, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>member we ſerve a good Maſter: Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, a
Neceſſity is laid upon us, we muſt Preach the Goſpel; and let us, be
contented, with that State and Portion we meet with in the World; 'tis our
great Buſineſs to approve our ſelves the Miniſters of Chriſt, <hi>in
La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, in Watchings, in Faſtings, by Pure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, by Knowledge, by the
Holy Ghoſt, by<pb n="132" facs="tcp:30333:75"/>Love unfeigned, by the Word of Truth, by
the Power of God, by the Armour of Righteouſneſs, on the Right Hand, and on
the Left; by Honour, and Diſhonour; by evil Report, and good Report,</hi> 2
Cor. 6.5,6,7,8. Poſſibly, we may be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proached, and ſenſured for what
we have done, and ſaid, in this ſmall Tract. But ſhould it be ſo, we
matter it not, ſince we have the Teſtimony of our Conſciences, that our
Deſign is the Glory of God, and the promoting his Bleſſed Goſpel in the
Nation, and the good of his poor Churches; and alſo, becauſe we know we
have the ſure Word of God to confirm the Truth of what we plead for:
VVhere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, whilſt we make it appear to all, 'tis not the Hire, the VVages,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi> that we aim at, but contrariwiſe, the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour of the ever
bleſſed God, and to VVitneſs to the Sanction of every one of his Juſt
and moſt Holy Precepts, we cannot be without Peace in our own Souls.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:30333:75" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
